我向你问好，小天使，亲爱的小天使迪玛丽亚，你好吗？
I greet you little angel, dear little angel Di María, how are you doing?
Te saludo angelito, querido angelito Di María, ¿cómo te va?
你好，马塞尔。
Hello, Marcel.
Hola, Marcel.
你好吗？
How are you?
¿Cómo estás?
一切都好吗？
All good?
¿Todo bien?
一切都很好。
Everything very good.
Todo muy bien.
首先，谢谢你。
First, thank you.
Primero, gracias.
你在葡萄牙吗？
Are you in Portugal?
¿Estás en Portugal?
天冷吗？
Is it cold?
¿Hace frío?
首先，提出一个强有力的问题。
First, ask a strong question.
Primero, haz una pregunta fuerte.
天冷了吗？
Is it getting cold?
¿Está haciendo frío?
不不。
No no.
No, no.
不，冷静。
No, calm down.
No, tranqui.
非常好。
It's pretty good.
Está bastante bien.
这里天气不好。
The weather is bad here.
Acá el clima zafa.
它不像欧洲那么多。
It is not as much as in Europe.
No es tanto como en Europa.
好吧，告诉我进展如何，你如何享受它，你记得如何。
Well, tell me how it's going, how you're enjoying it, how you're remembering.
Bueno, contame cómo te está yendo, cómo lo estás disfrutando, cómo estás recordando.
在葡萄牙的那一刻，你看到了自己的进球，我们看到了一个来自自行车踢球的进球，一个助攻。
the moment in Portugal, you see the goals you are scoring, we saw one from a bicycle kick, assists.
el momento en Portugal, uno ve los goles que estás haciendo, vimos uno de chilena, asistencias.
你看起来很舒服，请告诉我一些关于那部分的事情。
You seem comfortable, tell me a little about that part.
se te nota cómodo, contame un poco esa parte.
嗯，不，真的很好。
Well, no, really good.
Bueno, no, la verdad que bien.
我很高兴，事情进展顺利。
I'm happy, things are working out.
Estoy contento, las cosas están saliendo.
去年我们有一年...
Last year we had a year...
El año pasado tuvimos un año...
很困难，我们拿了很多分，但是嘿，最后......
difficult where we scored a lot of points, but hey, in the end...
difícil donde hicimos una gran cantidad de puntos, pero bueno, al final...
体育运动很激烈，但我们今年没能到达那里，但表现很好
Sporting was sharp and we couldn't get there and good this year
el Sporting estuvo afilado y no pudimos llegar y bueno este año
事情不一样了，战斗更加激烈，而我们就在那里，所以什么都没有
things are different, it's more fought and we're there so there's nothing really
las cosas están diferentes está más peleado y estamos ahí así que nada la verdad que
多么高兴，因为好吧，当事情进展顺利时......
How happy because well, when things go...
Que contento porque bueno, cuando las cosas van...
结果正在给出，整场比赛，足球。
The results are being given and the whole game, football.
se van dando los resultados y todo el juego, el fútbol.
它是单独出来的，事实是这让我平静。
It comes out alone and the truth is that that leaves me calm.
va saliendo solo y la verdad que eso me deja tranquilo.
今天，足球运动员在比赛的某个时刻告诉你我想享受最后的部分，这正在发生在你身上，就像你正在经历的那样。
Today the soccer player at a certain moment in the race tells you I want to enjoy the final part, this is happening to you as you are experiencing it.
hoy el jugador de fútbol en un determinado momento de la carrera te dice yo quiero disfrutar la parte final te está pasando eso como lo estás viviendo
是活着的。
is living.
está viviendo.
是的，是的，是的，现在
Yes, yes, yes, now
Sí, sí, sí, ya
两三年以来，我更加享受自己的感受。
two or three years in which I am enjoying how I feel much more.
dos o tres años en los que estoy disfrutando muchísimo más en lo que me voy sintiendo.
好多了，就像……相反，我想当你年轻的时候……
much better, it's like... like on the contrary, I think when you were younger...
mucho mejor, es como que... como al contrario, creo que cuando uno era más joven...
有时事情都很匆忙，匆忙，而今天......
Sometimes things were all rushed, rushed and today...
A veces las cosas eran todo apurado, apresurado y hoy...
如今，我更享受每场比赛、每一次训练。
And today I enjoy it more every game, every training session.
Y hoy en día la disfruto más cada partido, cada entrenamiento.
我正在努力过得更好。
I'm trying to have a much better time.
Como que intento pasarla mucho mejor.
当然，它也有点思考什么......
Surely it's also a little thinking about what...
Seguramente también es un poco pensando en lo que...
在剩下的一点点里，在剩下的一些年里，人们想尝试以另一种方式享受它
in the little that is left, in some years that are left and one wants to try to enjoy it in another way
en lo poco que va quedando, en algunos años que van quedando y uno quiere intentar disfrutar de otra manera
事实上，我已经这样做了两三年了，我很高兴，因为最终
and the truth is that I have been doing it this way for two or three years now and I am very happy because well in the end
y la verdad que lo estoy haciendo así ya hace dos o tres años y estoy muy feliz porque bueno al final
当你享受它时，事情也会在场上出现，它们会自己出现。
When you enjoy it, things also come out on the field, they come out on their own.
al disfrutarlo las cosas también dentro de la cancha salen salen solas
是的，这就是我要告诉你的，因为当玩家在不同的地方咨询他们时......
Yes, that's what I was going to tell you because when the player consults them in different places...
Sí, eso te iba a decir porque el jugador cuando los consultás en distintos lugares...
他们说我想享受最后一部分的层次顺序
order of hierarchy they say I want to enjoy the final part
orden de jerarquía dicen yo quiero disfrutar la parte final
但这并不能消除责任的程度，从你取得的进球以及球队内部的运作方式可以清楚地看出，但是......
But that does not take away the degree of responsibility, it is clear from the goals you have been scoring and from how it is functioning within the team, but...
Pero eso no le quita el grado de responsabilidad, está claro por los goles que venís haciendo y por cómo está funcionando dentro del equipo, pero...
我有时会想，你正在为即将到来的那部分做准备吗？
What I sometimes think is, are you preparing for that part that is coming?
Lo que a veces pienso es, te vas preparando para esa parte que viene?
一方面我有一个矛盾，Escalón，他总是说让我们享受这些人。
On the one hand I have a contradiction, Escalón and he always says let's enjoy it to these people.
Por un lado tengo una contradicción, Escalón y siempre dice disfrutemoslo a esta gente.
狮子座也是如此，当他们问他，你准备搬家了吗？你和你的家人谈谈吗？我知道这是一个
The same goes for Leo, when they ask him, are you preparing for the removal, do you talk to your family, which I know is a
lo mismo va para leo cuando le preguntan te vas preparando para el despuelo charlas con tu familia que sé que es un
重要的胸罩。
Important bra.
Sostén importante.
是的，你也说了一点，你正在准备，但是……
Yes, you said it a little too, you are preparing, but...
Sí, un poco lo dijiste también, te estás preparando, pero...
更喜欢享受这一刻
and one likes to enjoy this moment more
y uno como que disfruta más este momento
从另一个方面享受，因为需求，想要获胜，...
enjoying from another side, because the demand, the wanting to win, the...
el disfrutar desde otro lado, porque la exigencia, el querer ganar, el...
想要继续举起奖杯的愿望不会改变，这取决于你。
Wanting to continue lifting trophies doesn't change, that's up to you.
el querer seguir levantando trofeo no cambia, eso ya es de uno dentro.
他想在小比赛、训练中获胜，这一点永远不会改变，但是……
and he wants to win in the little games, in training and that will never change but...
y quiere ganar en los partiditos, en el entrenamiento y eso no va a cambiar nunca pero...
但从另一种意义上来说，很难解释以这种方式继续下去，带着这样的雄心。
But it is difficult to explain it, the other sense, to continue in that way, with that ambition.
Pero es difícil de explicarlo, el otro sentido, el seguir de esa manera, con esa ambición.
但同时在
but at the same time in
pero a la vez en
我认为当你年轻的时候你不会那样想，你试图赢得一切​​，你尝试......
I think that when you are younger you don't think about it that way, you try to want to win everything, you try...
Creo que cuando uno es más chico no lo piensa de esa manera, intenta querer ganarlo todo, intenta...
想要达到最
of wanting to reach the most
de querer llegar a lo más
不一样，是想放松一下头脑，继续
It's different, it's wanting to relax your head a little, continuing with the
es diferente, es el querer relajar un poco la cabeza, el seguir con la
满足需求，但同时享受每一个
with the demand, but at the same time enjoying each
con la exigencia, pero a la vez el el disfrutar de cada
这也很重要，没什么，我想我就是这样生活的。
It's important too and nothing, I think I'm living it that way.
es importante también y nada, creo que lo estoy viviendo de esa manera.
家人很高兴，因为他们也这么看我，所以...
The family is very happy because they see me that way too, so...
la familia está muy feliz porque me ve de esa manera también, entonces...
我不尝试任何事情来享受人们也看到我并享受它，这是一天结束时最重要的事情。
I try nothing to enjoy that people also see me and enjoy it and that is the most important thing at the end of the day.
nada intento disfrutar que la gente también me vea y que disfrute y eso es lo más importante al fin y al cabo
你知道吗，当我问马蒂亚斯时，我和小男孩们一起在桌子上工作，都是芭比娃娃
Do you know that I work here at the table with young boys, both Barbie, when I asked Matías
¿Vos sabés que yo trabajo acá en la mesa con chicos jóvenes, tanto Barbie, cuando les preguntaba a Matías
我们正在和阿里尔聊天，我说迪玛丽亚是什么？
and Ariel we were talking, I say what is Di María?
y Ariel estábamos hablando, digo ¿qué es Di María?
嗯，它让你处于一个非常高的位置
and well it put you in a very high place
y bueno te ponía en un lugar muy alto
但另一方面，就像一个人受到赞扬时，这就是我想问你的地方。
But on the other hand, it's like when a person receives praise and that's where I want to ask you.
pero del otro lado es como cuando le llega un elogio a una persona y ahí es donde te quiero preguntar
你如何定义自己？
How do you define yourself?
¿Cómo te definís?
因为我们说，他是一名精英球员，他们有不同的头脑。
Because we say, he is an elite player, they have a different head.
Porque nosotros decimos, es jugador de elite, tienen una cabeza distinta.
我是在对你们这些居高位的人说话。
I am speaking to you who occupy a very high place.
Te estoy hablando a ustedes que ocupan un lugar muy alto.
从你那里我知道你很简单，你很自然地走遍了整个地球，但是
from your place that I know that you are very simple and you are very natural to go down all the earth but
de tu lugar que sé que sos muy simple y sos muy natural para bajar toda la tierra pero
当你观察其他精英球员时，你如何定义精英球员？
How do you define that Elite player when you look at the other?
¿Cómo definís vos a ese jugador de Elite cuando vos mirás al otro?
因为你就是那样。
Because you are that.
Porque vos sos eso.
你如何定义精英，即不同首脑的等级制度？
How do you define the elite, the hierarchy with a different head?
¿Vos cómo definís al de élite, al de jerarquía con una cabeza distinta?
而我不知道，我知道什么，我唯一看到的永远是历史上最好的。
And I don't know, what do I know, the only one I see is always the best in history.
Y no sé, qué sé yo, yo siempre el único que veo es el mejor de la historia.
那么它就是不可能达到的最高点，而所有的
then it is the highest that it is impossible to reach and all the
entonces es lo más alto que eso es imposible llegar y todo el
其他一切都是...
Everything else is...
Todo lo demás están...
我的排名远远低于他，但是嘿，这个节目看到了他......
I ranked well below him, but hey, the show seeing him...
Escalone muy por debajo de él, pero bueno, el show verlo a él...
和他一起训练，有机会为俱乐部效力，看到
having trained with him, having had the opportunity to play for a club, seeing
el haber entrenado con él, el haber tenido la posibilidad de jugar en un club, el ver
每一次训练，关于他如何准备、他想要如何的全部事情
every training session, the whole thing about how he prepares, how he wants
cada entrenamiento, el el el el todo eso de de que cómo se prepara, cómo quiere
嘿他不喜欢
hey he doesn't like it
eh no le gusta
它是一般的一切，它完全是自己的一切。
It is everything in general, it is completely everything in oneself.
Es todo en general, es completamente todo en uno mismo.
我不知道，很难说，对吧？
I don't know, it's hard to say, right?
no sé, es difícil de poder decirlo, ¿no?
但我认为狮子座给了你这一切，对吗？
But I think Leo gives you all that, right?
Pero creo que Leo te da todo eso, ¿no?
一个人想成为什么
what one wants to be
lo que uno quiere ser
就是这样，传球最少的人，进球最多的人，助攻最多的人。
That's it, the one who passes the least R, the one who scores the most goals, the one who gives the most assists.
Es eso, el que menos pase R, el que más goles hace, el que más asistencia da.
哪一个是拥有最多奖杯的
which is the one with the most trophy
que es el que más trofeo tiene
那个，从你开始玩的那一刻起你总是尝试的，就是能够实现这个目标，对吗？
that one, and what you always try from the moment you start playing, is that, right?, to be able to achieve that goal.
que uno, y lo que intentas siempre desde que arrancas a jugar, es eso, ¿no?, llegar a poder lograr ese objetivo.
他们自然地告诉我们，我们生活在谈论你
They tell it with a naturalness that we live it talking about you
lo cuentan con una naturalidad que nosotros lo vivimos hablando de ustedes
但我想看看这个人的感受，因为你把自己放在另一个地方，我知道
but I wanted to see how the person feels because you put yourself in another place, I know that
pero quería ver cómo lo siente la persona porque vos te pones en otro lugar yo sé que
正如我们大家所说，我读到的内容是最好的。
What I read is, as we all say, the best of all.
que leo es como decimos todos el mejor de todos
确实，在训练中你不想失去任何东西
and it is so true that in training you do not want to lose anything that
y es tan cierto que ustedes en los entrenamientos no quieren perder a nada que
当你总是想着竞争，你要参加另一项运动时，他们会生气。
They get angry when you have that thing about competing all the time, you're going to play another sport.
que se enojan cuando esa cosa de que ustedes tienen de competir todo el tiempo, vas a jugar a otro deporte.
我不知道你是否知道。
I don't know if you do.
No sé si lo haces.
而你想赢，这也发生在你身上吗？
And you want to win, does that happen to you too?
Y querés ganar, ¿eso también te ocurre?
是的，是的，与一切，与一切。
Yes, yes, with everything, with everything.
Sí, sí, con todo, con todo.
对于任何运动，无论什么，你总是想赢。
With any sport, whatever, you always want to win.
Con cualquier deporte, con lo que sea, querés ganar siempre.
但我想这也是自己的吧？
But I think it's one's own too, right?
pero creo que ya es de uno mismo también ¿no?
我不知道，我想你在工作中也可能会遇到这样的情况：你总是想要更多，想要更多，
I don't know, I think it can also happen to you in your job that you will always want more and want more and
no sé creo que te puede pasar también en tu trabajo que siempre vas a querer más y querer más y
更远。
further.
más.
全部的。
Total.
我们都是一样的，都想赢，赢，赢，这会让你得到越来越多的机会
We are the same, that of wanting to win and win and win and that leads you to more and more eh
Nosotros lo mismo, ese de querer ganar y ganar y ganar y eso te va llevando a cada vez más eh
所以最终还是很难...
So in the end it is difficult to be able to...
Entonces al final es difícil de poder...
说精英，非精英，因为一个……我喜欢踢足球。
Saying that elite, non-elite, because one... I like to play soccer.
Decir eso de elite, de no elite, porque uno... A mí me gusta jugar al fútbol.
我努力在球场上享受乐趣，如果其他人也能享受到令我非常开心的乐趣，我会尝试
I try to have fun on the court and if the rest have fun that makes me very happy, I try
intento divertirme dentro de la cancha y si lo demás se divierten eso me me pone muy contento, intento
进球，做不同的事情。
score goals, do different things.
hacer goles, hacer cosas diferentes.
我觉得这是很自然的事情，也是一个人喜欢做的事情，所以最后就是这样
I think it is natural and what one loves to do, so in the end it is
creo que es lo natural de uno y lo que a uno le ama hacer entonces al final es
能说出这样的话是多么困难啊。
How difficult it is to be able to say those words.
como difícil de poder decir esas palabras.
你知道这是一个很特别的约会，也许我们越来越近了，我不知道这是否发生在你身上，
You know that it is a very special date, maybe we are getting closer, I don't know if it happens to you,
Vos sabés que es una fecha muy especial, nos estamos acercando tal vez, no sé si te pasa,
对我来说，就是通过 Instagram 记住我在卡塔尔经历的一切。
For me it is remembering through Instagram everything I experienced in Qatar.
A mi es recordar a través del Instagram todo lo que viví en Qatar.
真的有人有幸、有财富、有幸参加十届世界杯
really one had the happiness, the fortune, the privilege of being in ten world cups
realmente uno tuvo la dicha, la fortuna, el privilegio de estar en diez mundiales
两届冠军中唯一和你在一起的人正在接近决赛，那是你所经历的一切的史诗时刻
and the only one of the two-time champions with you is getting closer to the final, that epic moment of everything you experienced
y el único de los bicampeones con ustedes estamos acercándonos a la final, ese momento épico de todo lo que vivieron
当最后日期临近时，你会发生什么？
What's happening to you when the final date approaches?
qué te va pasando cuando se acerca la fecha de la final?
这些天你发生什么事了？
What's happening to you these days?
¿Qué te va pasando en estos días?
我不知道你是否喜欢看比赛和谈话。
I don't know if you're into watching games and talks.
No sé si sos de mirar los partidos y charlas.
你是否记得？
Do you remember?
¿Te acordás?
这个时候我们就在做这样的事情。
At this time we were doing such a thing.
A esta hora estábamos haciendo tal cosa.
不，事实是我所看到的一切都遵循网络上出现的一切，并且......
No, the truth is that what I look at follows everything that appears on the networks and...
No, la verdad que lo que miro sigue todo lo que sale en las redes y...
以及上传者和体育页面。
and the people who upload and the sports pages.
y la gente que sube y las páginas de deporte.
没什么，它让你怀旧
And nothing, it makes you nostalgic
Y nada, te genera una nostalgia
记住所有那些时刻...
to remember all those moments of...
de recordar todos esos momentos de...
不仅可以看到卡塔尔所经历的一切以及我们每天所经历的一切以及那里的人民和一切
to see not only everything that was being experienced in Qatar and what we were experiencing every day and the people and everything
de ver no solamente todo lo que se estaba viviendo en Qatar y lo que íbamos viviendo cada día y la gente y todo lo
人们在网络上看到的，还有阿根廷正在发生的事情，人们的情况，他们的生活方式。
that one saw on the networks, but also what was happening in Argentina, how the people were, how they were living it.
que uno veía en las redes, sino lo que también pasaba en Argentina, la gente cómo estaba, cómo lo estaba viviendo.
存在的幻觉。
the illusion that there was.
la ilusión que había.
老实说，我总是说同样的话，对吗？
Honestly, I always said the same thing, right?
Sinceramente, siempre dije lo mismo, ¿no?
绝不
Never
Nunca
我从来没有谈论过，也不喜欢谈论以前的世界杯。
I never talked nor do I like to talk about previous World Cups.
Nunca hablé ni me gusta hablar de los mundiales anteriores.
但我不知道他们过得怎么样，我没有机会去那里。
but I don't know how they have lived, I didn't have that chance to be there.
pero no sé cómo se han vivido, no tuve esa posibilidad de estar.
因为我还没有出生，但我不知道我的生活中没有这个
because I was not born, but I do not know this that I lived without
porque no había nacido, pero no sé esto que yo viví sin
说实话，这一个月里发生的一切都有些令人费解。
Honestly, everything that happened during that month is somewhat inexplicable.
Sinceramente es algo inexplicable todo lo que se vivió durante ese mes.
因为一切都是如何来的
because of how everything came
por cómo venía toda la
整个球队赢得的胜利、球队的表现以及一切，事实是，这很重要。
The whole wave of things that were being won and how the team played and everything, the truth is that it was something.
Toda la ola de cosas que se venía ganando y cómo jugaba el equipo y todo, la verdad que fue algo.
令人印象深刻的事情，它们是令人难忘的时刻
something impressive, they are unforgettable moments that
algo impresionante, son momentos inolvidables que
每次你看到它们，你都会看到它并想再次看到它。
Every time you see them, you see it and want to see it again.
cada vez que los ves, lo ves y lo querés volver a ver otra vez.
你知道明天就两年了，我看着马蒂、艾瑞尔和……
You know that tomorrow it will be two years and I look here at Mati, Ariel and...
Vos sabés que mañana van a ser dos años y miro acá a Mati, a Ariel y...
我的意思是，在这一切中，有一句话让我印象深刻：我们
I mean, in all this there was a phrase that stuck out to me that we
Digo, en todo esto hubo una frase que a mí me quedó que nosotros
就像在沟通部分说我坚持这句话
It's like in the communication part to say I'm holding on to this phrase
Es como en la parte comunicacional decir me agarro de esta frase
在中间，足球运动员身上发生了一些事情，因为他们有着令人难以置信的表现
and in the middle things happen that flow from the football players because they had an incredible performance
y en el medio van pasando cosas que fluyen desde los futbolísticos porque tuvieron un rendimiento increíble
输给阿拉伯后的第一句话
That first sentence after losing to Arabia
Aquella primera frase después de haber perdido con Arabia
我们不会让他们陷入困境，你还记得，从新闻的角度来看，我们都坚守着这里的所有地方。
that we are not going to leave them stranded. You remember that from the journalistic point of view of all the places here we all hold on to
que no los vamos a dejar tirados te acordás que nosotros desde lo periodístico de todos los lugares acá nos agarramos todos para
要找到正能量，请告诉我您对该短语的分配
To find positive energy, tell me what you assign to that phrase
para encontrar una energía positiva, contame vos qué le asignás a esa frase
后来他们通过比其他人打得更好而重新走上正轨，但这在空场比赛中非常重要。
Later they retraced their path by playing better than everyone else, but it was so important behind closed doors.
después fueron desandando el camino jugando mejor que todos los demás pero si fue tan importante puertas para adentro
是的，因为如果利奥这么说……
And yes, because if Leo says that...
Y sí, porque si Leo dice eso...
从他那里我们把一切都扔向同一个方向，所以如果他那样告诉你并说出来
from him and we throw everything in the same direction so if he tells you that way and says it
de él y y tiramos todo para el mismo lado entonces si él te lo dice de esa manera y lo dice
他在书中如此宽松地告诉我
and he told me so loosely in the
y me dijo tan sueltamente en la
发生了很多事情，因为
that a lot had happened because having
que había pasado un montón porque el haber
第一场比赛输掉了很多，发生的事情很疯狂。
Losing the first game was a lot, what had happened was crazy.
Perdidos el primer partido era un montón, era una locura lo que había pasado.
让他这样告诉你，让他放手
for him to tell you that way, for him to let it go
que él te lo diga de esa manera, que lo suelte
就好像什么都没发生过，什么也没有发生过一样，老实说……
as if nothing had happened and nothing, honestly...
como si nada hubiese pasado y nada, sinceramente...
关起门来，当我们都看到这句话时，它正在向前发展。
From behind closed doors, when we all saw that phrase, it was moving forward.
de puerta para adentro, cuando todos vimos la frase esa, era tirar para adelante.
我们知道事情将会有好的结果，最重要的是因为不仅因为他这么说，还因为在比赛中
and we knew that things were going to turn out well, more than anything also because not only because he said it, but because in the game
y sabíamos que la cosa iba a salir bien, más que nada también porque no solo porque lo dijo él, sino porque en el partido
你意识到发生了一些不可能发生的事情。
You realized that something had happened that couldn't happen.
Vos te dabas cuenta de que había pasado algo que no podía pasar.
这些都是奇怪的事情，发生的奥赛。
They were strange things, the orsai that happened.
Eran cosas raras, los orsai que pasaron.
我们每天都在他们玩的时候训练过的东西......
things that we had already trained every day that they played...
cosas que ya habíamos entrenado todos los días de que jugaban...
他们停下来了，我们必须保持冷静，我们不必着急。
that they stopped, that we had to be calm, that we didn't have to hurry.
que se paraban, que teníamos que estar tranquilos, que no teníamos que apurarnos.
但是想要赢得第一场比赛的焦虑，看到自己总是孤独的焦虑。
But the anxiety of wanting to win the first game, the anxiety that you saw that you were always alone.
Pero la ansiedad de querer ganar el primer partido, la ansiedad de que vos veías que te ibas siempre solo.
好吧，最终发生了我们不想发生的事情，但它确实发生了，留在了奥赛。
And that, well, ended up happening what we didn't want to happen and it happened, staying in Orsai.
Y eso, bueno, terminó pasando lo que no queríamos que pase y pasó, el quedarnos en Orsai.
所有的目标和一切，最终都结束了。
all the goals and everything and in the end it was over.
todos los goles y todo y al final terminó.
他们最终打进了两个伟大的进球，发生了什么事，但是那句话
They ended up scoring two great goals, well what happened happened but well that phrase
terminaban haciendo dos golazos que bueno pasó lo que pasó pero bueno esa frase
它将永远存在，因为从那时起，一切都再次变得对它有利。
It will remain forever because from then on everything turned in its favor again.
va a quedar para siempre porque a partir de ahí todo se puso otra vez a favor.
如果我把它变成那个地方，我想证实它是
If I turn it into that place I wanted to corroborate it as
si yo lo convierto en ese lugar quería corroborarlo como
我告诉人们，另一个声音是广播中非常有特色的声音，我们必须说我们正在和谁说话，以防有人上车。
The other one, I tell people, is a very characteristic voice on the radio. We have to say who we are talking to in case someone gets in the car.
la otra le digo a la gente es una voz muy característica en radio tenemos que decir con quién estamos hablando por si alguno se sube al auto lo que fue
这是最伟大的偶像，我将与人们一起经历那个反思的地方
which is the greatest idol of all and I am going to go through that place of reflection with the people
que es el ídolo máximo de todos y ya voy a transitar por ese lugar de reflexión con la gente
我
i
嘿，你知道明天我将与国家队球员和其他几位球员进行很多交谈，你知道这一点。
Hey, you know that tomorrow I'll talk a lot with the national team's players and with several others and you know it.
eh vos sabés que eh mañana yo charlo bastante con los futbolistas de la selección y con varios y lo sabés
我说，你当时发生了什么，因为你在决赛中我们不知道会发生什么？
I say, what happened to you when, because with you in the final we didn't know what was going to happen?
Yo digo, ¿qué te pasó cuando, porque con vos en la final no se sabía que iba a pasar?
如果您还记得的话，请告诉我今天，即 2022 年 17 日，情况如何。
Tell me what it was like today, the 17th of 2022, if you can remember.
contame como fue hoy 17 del 2022 si te puedes acordar
因为我认为事情的发展是动态的，当事情发生时就会有历史事实，这样你就能明白我想去的地方。
because I think it is a dynamic of things that as they happen there are historical facts so that you understand where I want to go.
porque creo que es una dinámica de cosas que a medida que pasan hay hechos históricos para que lo entiendas por donde quiero transitar
随着时间的推移，你会反思，越来越多的轶事会出现，因为你向所有主角敞开心扉
that over time you will reflect and more and more anecdotes will appear because you open up a little more to all the protagonists
que con el tiempo vas a ir reflexionando y van a aparecer cada vez más anécdotas porque vos te vas abriendo un poco más todos los protagonistas
这就是足球史、政治史，无论是怎样写的
And this is how the history of football, politics, whatever is written
Y así se escribe la historia del fútbol, de la política, de lo que fuere
所以我的目标是 2022 年 17 日。
So here I go and aim directly for that 17th of 2022.
Entonces ahí voy y apunto directamente a ese 17 del 2022.
因为不知道我是否可以参加比赛，如果我会选择你，那么后来你就拥有了电影中发生在你身上的一切
because it was not known if I could play, if I was going to choose you, well later you had everything you had as always happened to you in the movie
porque no se sabía si podía jugar, si te iba a elegir, bueno después tuviste todo lo que tuviste como te pasó siempre en la película
但告诉我那部分，让我们看看。
But tell me that part, let's see.
Pero contame esa parte, a ver.
真相与...
The truth with...
La verdad con...
老实说，这是一个糟糕的时刻，因为
It was honestly a shitty moment because
sinceramente era un momento de mierda porque
我唯一想要的就是能够参加决赛，我唯一想要的就是能够
and the only thing I wanted was to be able to play in that final, the only thing I wanted was to be able to
y lo único que deseaba era poder jugar esa final eh lo único que quería era poder
因为我觉得2014年发生在我身上的事情已经发生在我身上了，这是我的报复，是时候了。
because I felt that what had happened to me in 2014 had happened to me and it was my revenge, it was time.
porque sentía que me había pasado lo que me había pasado en el 2014 y era mi revancha, era el momento.
我已经做了
I had already done
ya venía de haber hecho
美洲杯、决赛和……的进球
the goals in the Copa América, in the final and...
los goles en la Copa América, en la finalísima y...
没什么，我想玩，因为我觉得是时候了，但是……
Nothing, I wanted to play because I felt it was time, but well...
Nada, quería jugar porque sentía que era el momento, pero bueno...
有教练，就有教练组。
There is a coach, there is a coaching staff.
Hay un entrenador, hay un cuerpo técnico.
那些日子就在那里，比赛前一天……
And those days were there, the day before the game was...
Y esos días ahí fueron, el día antes del partido fue...
因为我们要去训练，但我看到他没有上场
because we were going to train and I saw that he wasn't playing
porque porque íbamos a entrenar y y yo veía que no jugaba
像第五行一样停了下来，之后他让球停了下来，直接
had stopped like line five later he had made the ball stopped and directly
había parado como línea cinco después había había hecho la pelota parada y directamente
我已经用五行做到了，什么也没做，从那以后利奥也说过很多次了。
I had done it with the line of five and nothing and well Leo also said it a lot of times since
la había hecho con la línea de cinco y nada y yo bueno Leo también lo dijo un montón de veces ya que
没什么，我说，我不知道我是否玩，我玩，我不玩，你知道。
Nothing, I said, I don't know if I play, I play, I don't play, you know.
Que nada, que yo decía, no sé si juego, juego, no juego, vos sabés.
就好像你什么也没有尝试着找点什么可说的一样
It's like nothing you try to find something to say
es como que nada uno intenta encontrar algo que te que te que o decir
如果我坚持住，因为我要参加比赛，因为发生了这样的事情，我看到不，我看到不，不，不，好吧
and if I hold on inside because I'm going to play because such a thing happened and I saw that no, I saw that no, that no, that no and well
y si me agarro dentro porque voy a jugar porque pasó tal cosa y yo veía que no, veía que no, que no, que no y bueno
没什么，还是一如既往，我满怀热情地训练
nothing, just the same, as always, I train with enthusiasm
nada, igual, como siempre, entreno con gana
我会尽力而为，然后继续前进，如果是时间，就是时间，如果不是时间，那就不是时间。
I'll give it the best and move on, if it's time, it's time, and if it's not time, it's not time.
le meto la mejor y pa'lante, si le toca toca y si no toca no toca
但好吧，前一天就是这样的生活方式。
But well, that day before was that way of living.
Pero bueno, ese día antes fue de esa manera de vivir.
活在训练的每一秒，看看我是否能抓住某个说得好的地方......
Living every second of the training seeing if I could grab hold of somewhere that said well...
Vivir cada segundo del entrenamiento viendo si podía agarrarme de algún lado que diga bueno...
轮到我了，但那天什么也没有，没有任何征兆。
It's going to be my turn, but that day there was nothing, there was no sign.
Me va a tocar, pero ese día no había nada, no había ninguna señal.
当他告诉你是否轮到你时
at that sign when he tells you if this is your turn
en esa señal cuando él te dice si te toca esto
或者他们如何沟通？
Or how do they communicate it?
¿O cómo lo comunican?
他们在全球范围内进行交流吗？
Do they communicate it globally?
¿Lo comunican global?
怎么样？
How is?
¿Cómo es?
全球，全球是体育场之前的话题。
Global, global was the talk before there for the stadium.
Global, global fue la charla antes ahí para el estadio.
Axe，这么说吧，直到之前关于体育场、世界决赛的谈话之前，我都不知道他参加了比赛。
Axe, let's say, let's say until the talk before there for the stadium, for the world final, I didn't know he played.
Hacha, digamos, digamos hasta la charla antes ahí para el estadio, para la final del mundo, yo no sabía que jugaba.
这他妈的跟我有关。
It's fucking with me.
Me está jodiendo.
没有人知道我们是怎么玩的。
Nobody knew how we played.
Nadie sabía cómo jugábamos.
哦真的吗？
Oh really?
¿En serio?
我们不认为我们会做第 5 行，因为我在前一天就这样计划并训练了它。
We didn't think we were going to do line 5 because I had planned it that way and trained it that way the day before.
No pensábamos que íbamos a hacer línea 5 porque lo había planeado de esa manera y lo había entrenado de esa manera el día anterior.
所以...
So...
Entonces...
嗯，没什么，然后就在谈话中我们开始谈话，他说得好
eh nothing and then it was there in the talk we got into the talk and he said well
eh nada y después fue ahí en la charla entramos a la charla y dijo bueno
通常 Elisa 我们从这个 11 开始
Normally Elisa we start with this 11
normalmente Elisa arrancamos con este 11
然后球从沃尔特开始，最后他谈论了一些战术和一切
and then the ball starts with Walter and then he ends up talking a little about the tactics and everything
y después arranca la pelota parada con Walter y después termina él hablando un poco de los tácticos y todo
当他说好，这11个开始时，当然我看着屏幕，我没有看到自己，因为我只看着右侧。
And when he says well, these 11 start, of course I looked at the screen and I didn't see myself, because I just looked at the right side.
Y cuando él dice bueno arrancan estos 11, claro yo miré la pantalla y no me vi, porque yo miré el lado derecho nomás.
我说没有比赛，但当然后来我看到没有五人队我看到后面有四人
and I said no game but of course later I saw that there was no line of five I saw that there were four behind
y yo dije no juego pero claro después vi que no había línea de cinco vi que había cuatro atrás
然后我开始看，我发现我在左边，我做对了，现在我总是让 Lea Pared 坐在我旁边
and then I started to look and I saw that I was on the left side and I had it right, now I always have Lea Pared sitting next to me
y entonces empecé a mirar y me vi que estaba en el lado izquierdo y lo tenía justo, ahora tengo a Lea Pared sentada siempre al lado
他用眼角的余光看着我。
And he looks at me out of the corner of his eye.
Y me mira de reojo.
当然，你明白吗？
Sure, you see?
Claro, ¿viste?
它说...
And it says...
Y dice...
左边很奇怪，但是嘿，就是这样。
weird on the left side, but hey, that's it.
raro del lado izquierdo, pero bueno, ya está.
第一个目标是参加决赛。
The first objective was to play in the final.
El primer objetivo estaba que era jugar la final.
然后我们看到了如何解决在左边踢球的问题，但是......
Then we saw how we solved the problem of playing on the left, but...
Después veíamos cómo solucionábamos el problema de jugar por izquierda, pero...
但没什么，事实是，事情就是那样，事情就是那样，他们就是，就是……
But nothing, the truth is that it was like that, it was that way and they were, it was...
Pero nada, la verdad que fue así, fue de esa manera y fueron, fue...
有时看起来，嗯，这些都是时刻......
Sometimes it seems like, well, these are moments...
A veces pareciera como que, bueno, son momentos...
别担心，不，事实是这些都是非常紧张的时刻，因为你想要比赛，因为你想要成为
Don't worry, no, the truth is that these are very nervous moments because you want to play, because you want to be
tranqui, no, la verdad que son momentos de mucho nervio porque uno quiere jugar, porque uno quiere estar
没有什么，当我看到我在左边时，我的左腿像往常一样开始颤抖。
And nothing, once I saw that I was on the left side, my left leg started to shake, as always.
Y nada, a partir de que vi que estaba del lado izquierdo, la pierna izquierda empezó a temblar, como siempre.
他开始让我插进去，但事实是……
He started to start plugging me in there, but the truth is...
Empezó a empezar a enchufarme ahí, pero la verdad que...
当我看到我在左边时，我很高兴。
I was so happy when I saw that I was on the left side.
Que contento cuando me vi que estaba al lado izquierdo.
那是致命的。
That's deadly.
Eso es mortal.
我呼吁，法比安·库韦罗（Fabián Cubero）在这里与我或与我们一起工作。
I appeal, Fabián Cubero works here with me or with us.
Apelo, acá conmigo o con nosotros trabaja Fabián Cubero.
他总是问我们不在的舞台。我喜欢问，我很好奇。
He always asks about the stage that we are not living in. I like to ask, I am curious.
siempre le pregunta la etapa que no vivimos nosotros me gusta preguntar soy curioso
我想像专栏作家一样利用你，你也允许了。
And I want to take advantage of you almost like a columnist and you allow me.
Y te quiero aprovechar casi como un columnista y se me lo permitís.
迈出一步，他告诉你，嘿，来吧，在全球事件之后。
Step and he tells you, hey, come on, after the global thing.
Escalón y te dice, che, vamos, después de lo global.
技术演讲告诉你今天看我会把你放在左边为此
technical talk tells you look today I'll put you on the left for this for this for this
charla técnica te dice mira hoy te pongo por la izquierda por esto por esto por esto
在个人谈话中，不是与你一个人，而是与每个人，或者只是停留在你所看到的地方。
in the individual conversation, not with you alone, but with everyone or just stay with what you see.
en la charla individual, no con vos solo, sino con todos o simplemente se queda con eso que ustedes ven.
不，他说的话他在那里说，他和每个人一起跳舞，比方说。
No, what he speaks he speaks there and he dances it with everyone, let's say.
No, lo que habla lo habla ahí y lo baila con todos, digamos.
好的。
GOOD.
bien.
在演讲中，是的，是的，他解释了原因，并给了你
In the talk, yes, yes, he explains why and he gives you the
En la charla sí, sí, explica por qué y y te da la
解释为什么我们要这样玩，为什么
the explanation of why we are going to play like this, why
la la explicación de por qué vamos a jugar así, por qué
什么也没有，这就是他所做的，对吧？
And nothing, that's what he did, right?
Y nada, fue lo que hizo, ¿no?
他们看到他正往那个方向走。
They saw that he was going that way.
Vieron que por ese lado iba.
这就是为什么我能够进球，因为
and that's why in the goal I manage to score the goal because
y por eso en el gol yo llego a poder hacer el gol porque
我们在那里的谈话中。
in the talk when we were there.
en la charla cuando estábamos ahí.
她告诉我，有时我应该尽量摆脱困境，就像利奥有时呆在那里时所做的那样。
She had told me that at times I should try to stay a little off the hook, like Leo sometimes does when he stays there.
Ella me había dicho que por momentos intente quedarme como un poco descolgado, como se queda Leo a veces que se queda por ahí.
绕了一圈，他希望我留在左侧半松，因为我们可以在哪里恢复
going around, he wanted me to stay there on the left side half loose because where we could recover we could
dando vueltas, él quería que yo me quede ahí por el lado izquierdo medio suelto porque en la que podíamos recuperar podíamos
快点出去，我希望它永远是半开的。
get out quickly and I wanted it to always be half open.
salir rápido y quería que siempre esté medio abierto.
好吧，没什么，就在那里，比赛发生在我们反对的地方，我开始跑到另一边。
And well, nothing, right there the play happened where we went against it and I started running on the other side.
Y bueno, nada, justo ahí se dio la jugada esa que salimos de contra y yo arranqué a correr por el otro lado.
所以没什么，再好不过了。
so nothing, it couldn't be better.
así que nada, mejor imposible.
告诉我，当斗牛即将到来时，你是否没有感觉到……
Tell me if you didn't feel when the bullfight was coming...
Decime si no te sentiste cuando venía la corrida...
如果你感觉不像尤塞恩·博尔特，那为什么离你那么远呢？
If you didn't feel like Usain Bolt, why was it so far away?
Si no te sentiste Usain Bolt, ¿por qué era lejísimo?
因为跑步看起来很自然。
Because the run seems so natural.
Porque parece tan natural la corrida.
斗牛发生在游戏的某个时刻。
The bullfight takes place at a certain moment in the game.
La corrida se da a un determinado momento del partido.
我们所看到的一切都必须给予，我们将看到它，我们永远不会厌倦，因为这都是一流的触感
It is that everything we have seen has to be given and that we are going to see it and we are never going to get tired because it is all first-class touch
es que se tiene que dar todo lo que hemos visto y que la vamos a ver y no nos vamos a cansar nunca porque es todo toque de primera
但当然，你在另一端，我说，你会看到会发生什么。
But of course, you're on the other end and I say, you're going to see what's going to happen.
Pero claro, vos estás en la otra punta y digo, vais a ver que le va a llegar.
你必须有那种进球的乐观精神，我称之为，一个不知道如何比赛的冠军。
You have to have that goal-scoring optimism, what I call it, of a champion who doesn't know how to play.
Tienes que tener ese optimismo del gol, que le llamo yo, de un champón que no sabe jugar.
告诉我那个声音，你感觉到 6 个球在跑
tell me the voice and you felt 6 balls running
contame la voz y te sentiste 6 ball corriendo
不，我就像一个球迷，可以说，我正在观看整场比赛。
No, I was like the fan, let's say, I was watching the whole play.
No, yo estaba como la hinchada, digamos, yo estaba viendo toda la jugada.
我作为一个旁观者在场，我是一个旁观者观看了整场比赛。
I was there as a spectator, I was a spectator watching the whole play.
Yo estaba ahí de espectador, yo estaba de espectador mirando toda la jugada.
我开始了解提基塔卡的情况，提基塔卡的情况如何，我要告诉你我做了什么
and I began to see how the tiquitaca, the tiquitaca how it was going and I'm going to tell you what I did
y empecé a ver como el tiquitaca, el tiquitaca como iba y yo le voy a decir lo que hice
我总是做的事情是，当我看到比赛正在进行时，我开始跑向太空并开始奔跑。
What I always do, I started running into space and started running when I saw that the play was going.
lo que hago siempre, empecé a correr al espacio y arranqué a correr a correr cuando vi que la jugada iba.
当我看到球回到亚历克西斯身边时，就在那时......
And when I saw that the ball was coming back to Alexis, that's when...
Y cuando ya vi que la pelota le llega a Alexis de vuelta es cuando...
有一种触摸反应最终可能会发生在我这边。
There is a touch reaction that can end up on my side.
hay un toque reacciono que puede terminar de mi lado.
到目前为止我们只玩另一边
so far as we are playing only the other side
hasta el momento como estamos jugando solo el otro lado
因为最后看起来比赛进展得很快。
because in the end it seems like the play is very fast.
porque al final parece como que la jugada es rapidísima.
因为它非常快，但对于我们在那里的人来说也不是那么回事，因为
because it is very fast but for us who are in there it is not so like that either because
porque es rapísima pero para nosotros que estás ahí adentro no es tan así tampoco porque
它有它的触感，它的动作，它会发生......
It has its touches, its movements and it sort of happens...
tiene sus toques, sus movimientos y como que va transcurriendo...
当他做胡卷的时候，时间一分一秒地过去了
Seconds pass while he is doing the juan then
va pasando segundos mientras va haciendo la juan entonces
就像你正在读一切是如何进行的，而当我开始看到狮子座发生了什么事时
It's like you're reading how everything is going and when I started to see what happened to Leo
es como que vas leyendo cómo va todo y yo cuando empecé a ver que le llegó a Leo
我已经开始做出一些想要跑步的小动作了。
Already there I began to make a little movement of starting to want to run.
ya ahí ya empecé a hacer un poco de movimiento de empezar a como a querer correr
因为你已经知道，当狮子座到达时，他们很少会失去它，也很少会带走它。
because you already know that when Leo arrives it is very rare for them to lose it, it is very rare for them to take it away.
porque vos ya sabés que cuando les llega Leo es muy raro que la pierda, es muy raro que se la saquen.
更重要的是，当你反对它时，它总是会扭转，它总是会坚持下去，或者很容易解决它。
and even more so when you go against it, it always turns, it always holds up or it solves it easily.
y más saliendo de contra, siempre gira, siempre la aguanta o te resuelve fácil.
所以当它到达他那里时就好像它已经在那里了
so when it reaches him it's like it's already there
entonces cuando le llega a él es como que ya ahí ya
我开始对触摸做出反应，当触摸到来时
and I started to react to a touch and when it comes
y empecé a reaccionar un toque y cuando le llega
我开始看得更清楚了，当球传给亚历克斯时，他独自一人......
I'm starting to see it a little more clearly and when the ball goes to Alex and he goes alone...
empiezo a verlo un poco más claro y cuando la pelota le va a Alex y que va solo...
我开始意识到我最终可能会站在我这边，就像亚历克西斯也可以做的那样......
I began to realize that I could end up on my side, like Alexis could have done too...
me empecé a dar cuenta que podía terminar por mi lado, como también Alexis podía haber hecho...
再触球一次，我就踢进了球门，但是，嘿，他完美地看到了我，让我完美地完成了射门。
One more touch and I kicked the goal, but hey, he saw me perfectly and left it impeccable for me to finish.
un toque más y pateé al arco, pero bueno, me vio perfecto y me la dejó impecable para definir.
我只告诉你这个，仅此而已。
I'm going to tell you this, nothing more.
Yo te voy a decir esto, nada más.
你是否让我想起了小时候，你在一流的足球比赛中取得了成绩？
Have you reminded me of the time when I was a kid, that you made grades in first-class soccer?
¿Me has acordado a la época de que yo era pibe, que vos te hacías notas yo en fútbol de primera?
因为穆尼奥斯和维克多·雨果在舞台上留下了深刻的印象，让得分手听到了这样一个事实：他一定已经不再是个孩子了
because Muñoz and Víctor Hugo, who marked a stage, made the scorer listen to the fact that he must have grown out of being a kid
porque Muñoz y Víctor Hugo, que marcaron una etapa, le hacían escuchar al goleador que habrá pasado de pibe
这让他听到了进球的声音。
that made him listen to the goal.
que le hacían escuchar el gol.
我们开始制作这个电台，Disporradio，这是一个体育电台。
We started on this radio, Disporradio, which is a sports radio.
Nosotros arrancamos en esta radio, Disporradio, que es una radio deportiva.
它已经成长，我们从卡塔尔开始，想象一下......
that has grown and we start with Qatar, imagine...
que ha crecido y empezamos con Qatar, imaginate...
赢得冠军，你明白吗？
Winning a title, you understand?
Ganando un título, ¿entendés?
想象。
Imagine.
Imagínate.
好吧，好吧。
Well, well.
Bueno, bien.
好吧，鸡说。
Well, the chicken said.
Bueno, relataba el pollo.
恩里克·马卡亚·马尔克斯评论道，无论谁和你说话都会说你看到了我对马卡亚的迷恋。
Enrique Macaya Marquez commented and whoever is talking to you would say you saw in those things I got hung up on Macaya.
comentaba enrique macaya marquez y quien te habla dirían viste en esas cosas me colgué de macaya yo
但是听着，请允许我谈谈，听听他们如何看待你亲自讲述的内容。
But listen, allow me on this, listen to how they saw what you told in person.
Pero escuchá, permíteme en esto, escuchá como vieron lo que vos relataste en persona
这就是塞巴斯蒂安对进球的看法。
This is how Sebastián saw it in the goal.
Así lo veía Sebastián en el gol.
如果麦卡利斯特走了，如果他走了，如果麦卡利斯特走了，麦卡利斯特将其更改为Golden Ibarria，将其更改为Golden Fideo Cantaro
If Macalister goes, if he goes, if Macalister goes, Macalister changes it to Golden Ibarria, changes it to Golden Fideo Cantaro
Se va Macalister, se va, se va Macalister, Macalister la cambia a Golden Ibarria, la cambia a Golden Fideo Cantaro
¡坎塔洛，坎塔洛，坎塔洛，坎塔洛！
¡Cantalo, cantalo, cantalo, cantalo!
¡目标，目标，目标，目标，目标，目标，目标，目标！
¡Goals, goals, goals, goals, goals, goals, goals, goals!
¡Gol, gol, gol, gol, gol, gol, gol, gol!
戈尔！
¡Gol!
快点！
Come on!
¡Vamos!
阿根廷面条！
Argentinian the Noodle!
¡Argentino el Fideo!
菲迪奥·迪·玛丽亚！
The Fideo Di María!
¡El Fideo Di María!
女士们先生们，这是一个令人难忘的柜台。
Ladies and gentlemen, an unforgettable counter.
Señoras y señores, una contra inolvidable.
一个精确而珍贵的计数器，因为它咬住了，因为它恢复了。
A precise and precious counter because it bit, because it recovered.
Una contra precisa y preciosa porque mordió, porque recuperó.
足球运动员莫利纳碰了一下，但麦卡利特把球拿了出来。
The soccer player Molina touched but Macaliter took it out.
El futbolista Molina tocó pero Macaliter la sacó.
就好像他是迭戈一样，他已经为查韦斯波尔出现过，就好像他是楚蒂一样，为布鲁查加效力过
as if he were Diego, he already appeared for Chávez Pol as if he were Chuty and played for Burruchaga
como si fuese Diego, ya apareció para Chávez Pol como si fuese Chuty y tocó para Burruchaga
在我们看来，迪玛利亚在左边，就好像他是巴尔达诺，先生们，是的，相信它，相信它
Di María seemed to us on the left as if he were Valdano, gentlemen, yes, believe it, believe it
nos pareció por izquierda a Di María como si fuese Valdano señores, sí, creélo, creélo
86 年，伊巴利亚的面条似乎取得了成功。
Fire in '86, Ibaría's noodle appeared to score.
Fuego en el 86, apareció el fideo de Ibaría para marcar.
本场比赛第二粒进球阿根廷2-0法国接近荣耀
the second goal of the game gentlemen argentina 2 france 0 close to glory
el segundo gol del partido señores argentina 2 francia 0 cerca de la gloria
临近杯赛 临近世界杯 咱们走国家队 咱们阿根廷走吧 一颗这么大的心
close to the cup close to the world cup let's go national team let's go from argentina a heart this big for
cerca de la copa cerca del mundial vamos selección vamos de argentina un corazón así de grande para
每个人都有一颗这么大的心，涂成浅蓝色
everyone has a heart this big painted in light blue
todo el mundo un corazón así de grande pintado en celeste
阿根廷2，法国0，迪马利亚
Argentina 2, France 0, Di María
Argentina 2, Francia 0, Di María
菲迪奥哭了，你哭了，我们哭了，每个人都哭了，阿根廷就这样迈出了一小步。
Fideo cries, you cry, we cry, everyone cries, Argentina takes a little step like that.
Lloran Fideo, lloras vos, lloramos nosotros, lloran todos, Argentina un pasito así.
玛丽亚的荣耀 阿根廷 2 法国 0
of the glory of María Argentina 2 France 0
de la gloria de maría argentina 2 francia 0
出于显而易见的原因，我们删除了我的评论部分，你看，因为我们要把它撕下来，小天使。
For obvious reasons, we cut the part of my comment, you see, because we are going to tear it down, little angel.
Por razones obvias, cortamos la parte del comentario mío, viste, porque le vamos a tirar abajo, angelito.
因为没有必要，收音机非常好。
because it wasn't necessary, the radio was very good.
porque no era necesario, estuvo muy bien la radio.
但我留下来，我记得你的脸
but I'm staying, I'm remembering your face
pero me estoy quedando estoy acordándome de tu cara
我看到了你的脸和那颗心的倒影，因为小鸡塞巴斯蒂安所说的一切
I'm seeing the reflection of your face and that heart because everything Sebastian the Chicken says
estoy viendo el reflejo de tu cara y ese corazón porque todo lo que dice Sebastián el Pollo
这与你脸上所传达的信息有关，今天当你看到那个兴奋的图像时，从远处告诉我一些关于它的信息。
It has to do with what you conveyed about your face, tell me a little about it today from a distance when you see that excited image.
tiene que ver con eso de lo que transmitías vos de tu cara contame un poco hoy a la distancia cuando ves esa imagen emocionada
不，这就是我想要的。
No, it was what... what I wanted.
No, era lo que... lo que deseaba.
正如我之前告诉过你的，从前一天开始
As I told you before, from the day before
como te dije antes, ya del día antes
自从我们进入决赛以来，我的愿望就是参加比赛。
Since we went to the final, my desire was to play.
Desde que pasamos a la final, el deseo mio era jugar.
就是玩，玩，玩。
It was play, play, play.
Era jugar, jugar, jugar.
无论如何，在我们进入决赛之后。
anyway, after we move on to the finals.
como sea, después de que pasamos a la final.
嗯，就在同一天，距离决赛还有一切
eh that same day still from the final and everything still had
eh el ese mismo día todavía de la final y todo todavía tenía
如果它还没有完全消失，那么第二天
in which and if it had not completely gone and the next day
en el cual y si no se me había ido del todo y al día siguiente
什么都没有，我唯一想要和渴望的就是到达，我梦想着那
nothing at all and the only thing I wanted and desired was to arrive, I dreamed of that
a todo nada y lo único que quería y deseaba era llegar, soñaba con ese
我梦见了那个游戏...
I dreamed of that game...
Con ese partido soñaba...
因为真诚地，它是其中之一
because sincerely it is the one of the
porque porque sinceramente se me es el el del
使幻象失控。
taken the illusion out of hand.
sacado la ilusión de las manos.
我非常想要那个
I have wanted that so much
que me he deseado tanto ese
谁让我抽烟就像什么都没有并且有这种可能性
who smoked me like it was nothing and and having this possibility
que me fumó como si nada y y tener esta posibilidad
我不想浪费它，我不想不，不，不，不，不能玩它，不能……
I didn't want to waste it, I didn't want no, no, no, no, not being able to play it, not being...
No quería desaprovecharla, no quería que no, que no, no, no, no poder jugarla, no estar...
这是我最想要的，我觉得这就是那个时刻，它也伴随着决赛早些时候的进球而来。
It was what I wanted most, I felt it was the moment, it also came with the goals earlier in the final.
Era lo que más deseaba, sentía que era el momento, ya venía también con los goles antes en la final.
就好像我内心有一种很大的感觉，但什么也没有，当他说有一个目标时，就像……
It's like I had a very big feeling inside and nothing, when he says there's a goal it's like...
Es como que tenía un sentimiento dentro muy grande y nada, cuando dice hay gol es como que...
我因感谢迭戈而产生的所有感觉都爆发了
all that feeling I had from thanking Diego exploded
explotó todo ese sentimiento que tenía el agradecerle al Diego
感谢他一直都在，因为美洲杯决赛我曾请求他帮助我。
for always being there, because the Copa América final I had asked him to give me a hand.
por estar siempre, porque la Copa América de la final que le había pedido que me de una mano.
等等，什么也没有，我的家人知道他们在那里
and so on and nothing, my family knew they were there
y así sucesivamente y nada, mi familia sabía que estaban ahí
他们不可能在上一场决赛中看到我，而且他们都是一样的。
They couldn't have seen me in the previous final and they had all been the same.
No me podían haber visto en la final anterior y habían estado todos los mismos.
在那场决赛中，然后就什么都没有了，我拥有了很多东西......
In that final, then nothing, I had so many things...
en esa final, entonces nada, tenía tantas cosas...
这个目标让我内心充满了喜悦。
Inside me that goal exploded all that joy.
Dentro mío que el gol explotó toda esa alegría.
以及我内心的那种情感。
and that emotion I had inside.
y esa emoción que tenía adentro.
心何时生？
When is the heart born?
¿Cuándo nace lo del corazón?
而这颗心是在2000年诞生的……
And the heart was born in 2000...
Y el corazón nació en el 2000...
2010 年 9 月 9 日，在葡萄牙，当时他来和我的朋友住在一起。
9, 2010, here in Portugal, when he came to live with my homie.
9 de 2010, acá en Portugal, cuando se vino a vivir con mi homie.
我妻子到达的第一天，第二天我们就在玩......
The first day my wife arrived, the next day we were playing and...
Mi mujer el primer día que llegó, al otro día jugábamos y...
他在主场打进一球，从此永远留存。
He scored a goal at home and from there it stayed forever.
hizo un gol de local y a partir de ahí quedó para siempre.
多么野蛮，因为玩家不同
how barbaric because the player is different
qué bárbaro porque el jugador el distinto
你已经看到了某些事情，今天男孩们模仿你
You have seen certain things and today the boys copy you
tiene viste determinadas cosas y hoy los chicos te copian
有些人像我读到的那样举起两个手指
There are those who put their two fingers up like I read
están los que ponen los dos dedos hacia arriba como leo
迭戈喊道，这是跳跃和挥动左手的动作，我正在广播中做这个动作
Diego shouted that it was that gesture of jumping and swinging his left hand, I'm doing the movement here on the radio
grito de Diego que era ese gesto de saltar y revolear su mano izquierda lo estoy haciendo el movimiento acá en la radio
你们是发自内心的，你们会看到他们用心庆祝。
And yours from the heart, you guys will see that they celebrate with their hearts.
Y el tuyo del corazón, los chicos vos lo verás que festejan con el corazón.
是的，是的，我确实看到了，而且我收到了很多视频……
Yes, yes, I do see it and I get a lot of videos and...
Sí, sí, sí lo veo y me llegan muchos videos y...
很多次我都会发送生日快乐视频以及他们向我提出的所有要求
and many times I send happy birthday videos and everything or things they ask of me
y muchas veces que mando videos de feliz cumpleaños y todo o cosas que me piden
然后他们给我发了一段视频，感谢孩子们，他们总是竭尽全力，但什么也没做，事实是……
Then they send me back a video thanking the kids and always doing their heart out and nothing, the truth is...
después me devuelven un videíto agradeciendo a los nenes y siempre haciendo el corazón y nada, la verdad que...
这让我很高兴，有一个人作为偶像、作为参考或作为……是一件非常好的事情。
That makes me happy, it is something very nice to have someone as an idol, as a reference or as...
que me pone feliz, es algo muy lindo que a uno lo tengan como ídolo, como referente o como...
不管你想怎么称呼它，经过了这么多年、这么多年
whatever you want to call it, after so many years and so much
como quiera llamarlo, después de tantos años y de tanto
在足球领域。
in football.
en el fútbol.
它现在具有如此巨大的价值，所有这些孩子都这样做，对我来说这很美丽。
That it has such great value now and all those kids do that, for me it's beautiful.
que tenga ese valor tan grande ahora y todos esos nenes hagan eso, para mí es hermoso.
这正是我想问你的，你是否觉得自己会在最糟糕的时刻扭转局面？
That's exactly what I was going to ask you, did you feel like you were going to turn it around at the worst moment?
Justamente eso te iba a preguntar, ¿sentiste que lo ibas a dar vuelta en el peor momento?
很难...你知道我为什么问你这个吗？
difficult to be able to... Do you know why I ask you this?
difícil de poder... ¿Sabés por qué te lo pregunto?
让我告诉你是因为我问你是因为有时当你在做一个项目时你会想到逆境中的挣扎。
to let me tell you because I'm asking you because sometimes when you're doing a program you think about the struggle of adversity.
para dejarme contartelo porque te lo pregunto porque a veces uno en el cuando está haciendo un programa piensa en la lucha de la adversidad
还有更多的人。
of many more people.
de mucha más gente.
有时我给你举个例子，不是因为你寻找它或已经寻找它，
And sometimes I give you as an example, not because you look for it or have looked for it,
Y a veces te pongo como un ejemplo, no porque vos lo busques o lo haya buscado,
但因为人类存在着永久的斗争，嘿，我该如何扭转这一点？
but because there is the permanent struggle of human beings of, hey, how do I twist this?
sino porque está la lucha permanente del ser humano de, che, ¿cómo tuerzo esto?
我该如何克服问题？
How do I overcome a problem?
¿Cómo supero un problema?
事实上，你在观看这部连续剧和一些关于你的家庭的事情时，内心就已经根深蒂固了，我认为这是一个超凡的支柱。
And you had that thing entrenched inside, well, in fact, watching the series and a little bit about your family, which I think is a transcendent prop.
Y vos tenías esa cosa enquistada adentro, bueno, de hecho ver la serie y un poco tu familia, que creo que es un puntal trascendente.
但我想，我从来没有问过你，我只是等待那一刻。
but I wanted to, I had never asked you and I waited for the moment.
pero quería nunca te lo había preguntado y esperé el momento es
你觉得你要扭转局面，因为你扭转了局面，但我是在那一刻说的。
You felt like you were going to turn it around because you turned it around but I say at that moment.
sentías que lo ibas a dar vuelta porque lo diste vuelta pero digo en ese momento
你们的战斗是什么样的？
What was your fight like?
¿Cómo era tu lucha?
我说，不，我继续。
And I say, no, I continue.
Y digo, no, yo sigo.
我不知道，告诉我那部分，我会以某种方式介绍给你。
I don't know, tell me that part there, I'll introduce you in some way.
No sé, contame ahí esa parte, te voy introduciendo de alguna manera.
不，你之前告诉过我，是家人。
No, you told me before, the family.
No, me lo dijiste vos antes, la familia.
因为归根结底，家庭就是一切
because at the end of the day family is everything
porque la familia al fin y al cabo lo es todo
当事情不好的时候他们会在那里，当事情好的时候他们不会在那里，因为因为
They are the ones who are there when things are bad and when things are good they are not the ones who are there because because
son los que están cuando las cosas van mal y cuando las cosas están bien no son los que están ahí porque porque
对于他们来说，我们又是一个人，我们是一家人。
For them we are one more, we are family.
para ellos somos uno más, somos la familia.
我是米格尔和戴安娜的儿子，我是乔吉丽娜的丈夫，
I am the son of Miguel and Diana, I am the husband of Jorgelina, the
soy el hijo de Miguel y Diana, soy el marido de Jorgelina, el
我不是那样的人，但是当事情出错时......
I'm not that one, but when things go wrong...
No soy ese, pero cuando a uno le va mal...
如果我们是那些人，如果我们是批评者……
If we are those, if we are the one who criticizes the...
Si somos esos, si somos al que critican al...
致受伤的王八蛋，致不想参加总决赛的王八蛋
to the son of a bitch who gets injured, to the son of a bitch who doesn't want to play in the finals
al hijo de puta que se lesiona, al hijo de puta que no quiere jugar las finales
这就是我们所处的位置，就是当家人在那里的时候，当他们让你坐板凳的时候，当他们出来保护你的时候。
That's where we are and that's when the family is there, when they bench you, when they come out to defend you.
Ahí sí somos y ahí sí es cuando la familia está, cuando te banca, cuando te sale a defender.
当他和你一起受苦，当他和你一起哭泣，最后……
when he suffers with you, when he cries with you, then in the end...
cuando sufre con vos, cuando llora con vos, entonces al final...
他们给了你继续前进、继续战斗、继续战斗的力量。
They are the ones who give you that strength to continue, to continue fighting, to continue fighting.
Son ellos los que te dan esa fuerza para seguir, para seguir luchándola, para seguir peleando.
我知道什么
what do I know
que se yo
工具和那些最终不会让你跌倒的东西你不认为我会扭转局面，而是
tool and those that don't let you fall in the end you don't think I'm going to turn it around but rather
herramienta y los que no te dejan caer al final uno no piensa lo voy a dar vuelta sino que
你拥有所有人是什么？
what is it that you have everyone
que es que tenés a a toda
你会成功的。
you're going to make it.
lo vas a lograr.
我继续说道。
I continued.
Seguí.
不，不要放下你的手臂。
No, don't lower your arms.
No, no baje los brazos.
为什么你要允许自己被践踏，或者为什么你要让自己被践踏？
Why are you going to allow yourself to be trampled on or why are you going to let yourself be trampled?
¿Por qué te vas a dejar que te pisoten o por qué te vas a dejar que
如果你看看你赢得了什么，就让他们超越你吧
Let them pass you over, if you looked at what you won
que te pasen por arriba, si miraste lo que ganaste
在你的职业生涯中。
during your career.
durante tu carrera.
为何要让自己被践踏？
Why are you going to let yourself be trampled?
¿Por qué te vas a dejar pisotear?
因为事物不知道选择。
Because things don't know the selection.
Porque las cosas no saben la selección.
如果你身体还好，如果你继续做正确的事情，就继续努力。
Keep trying, if you're still physically well, if you keep doing things right.
Seguí intentándolo, si todavía estás bien físicamente, si seguís haciendo las cosas bien.
不！
¡No!
所以你也要继续这样做，因为你背后有人，​​有人在你身后把你推上板凳等死。
So you continue for that too, because you have someone behind you, you have people behind you who are benching you to die.
Entonces uno sigue por eso también, porque tenés a alguien atrás, tenés gente atrás que te está bancando a morir.
什么也没有，一个人做了并且显然在想......
And nothing, one does and obviously thinks...
Y nada, uno sí y obvio que piensa...
我最终会赢，我想赢，我想在国家队取得一些成就。
I'm going to end up winning, I want to win it, I want to achieve something with the national team.
Voy a terminar ganando, lo quiero ganar, quiero lograr algo con la selección.
但你不知道这是否会发生，对吧？
but you don't know if it's going to happen, huh?
pero no sabés si va a pasar, ¿eh?
有多少人通过了选拔？
How many went through the selection?
¿Cuántos pasaron por la selección?
不幸的是，我认为他们应该能够为他们所付出的一切取得一些成就，但他们却做不到。
and unfortunately I think they deserved to be able to achieve something for everything they gave them and they couldn't.
y lamentablemente creo que se merecían poder lograr algo por todo lo que le dieron y no pudieron.
最终有时它并没有发生，但尝试并不需要付出任何代价。
In the end sometimes it doesn't happen, but trying doesn't cost anything.
al final a veces no se da, pero el intentarlo no cuesta nada.
并且继续为自己的梦想而奋斗并不困难，所以你要不断地投入其中。
And trying to continue fighting for what you dream of is not difficult either, so you keep putting yourself into it.
Y el intentar seguir luchando por lo que uno sueña tampoco cuesta, entonces uno le sigue metiendo.
换句话说，最终是家人告诉你，你必须继续前进，你必须继续前进，站起来并继续前进。
In other words, it is ultimately the family that told you that you have to keep going, you have to keep going, get up and keep going.
O sea que es la familia en definitiva la que te dijo hay que seguir, hay que seguir, levantate y seguí.
是的，是的，是的。
Yes, yes, yes.
Sí, sí, sí.
家人
the family
la familia.
是的，是的，就是这个，就是这个
Yes, yes, it is the it is the
Sí, sí, es la es la
一个人可以继续，一个人可以继续尝试，但如果没有家族的力量和家族的毅力。
One can continue and one can continue trying, but if one does not have the strength of the family and the perseverance of the family.
Uno puede seguir y puede seguir intentándolo, pero si no tiene la fuerza de la familia y la constancia de la familia.
在那些时刻继续银行业务，呃，这很困难，因为有时
to continue banking in those moments, eh, it's difficult because sometimes
de seguir bancándote en esos momentos eh es difícil porque a
有的受的苦一点，没有那个力气，因为我回答过好几次了
Some suffer a little more and do not have that strength because I answered it several times that
algunos sufren un poco más y no tienen esa fuerza porque yo lo contesté a mi varias veces que
有那么一刻，我妈妈告诉我，就是这样，儿子，你还要让他们践踏你吗？
There was a moment when my mother told me, that's it, son, how much more are you going to let them walk all over you?
que hubo un momento en que mi mamá me dijo, ya está hijo, ¿cuánto más vas a dejar que te pisoteen?
那么那时我就可以
then that's when I can
entonces ahí es cuando capaz
给我的妻子，她告诉我你不必继续，因为你不会继续战斗。
to my wife and she told me you don't have to continue because you are not going to continue fighting.
a mi mujer y me decía no tenés que seguir porque no vas a seguir luchando
如果穿上国家队球衣是你的梦想，那就是你的梦想。
If it is your dream to wear the national team shirt, it is your dream.
Si es tu sueño vestir la camiseta de la selección es tu sueño.
继续实现，继续为实现某些目标的梦想而奋斗，但与此同时，我继续实现这个梦想
keep fulfilling, keep fighting for that dream of achieving something, but in the meantime I continued with that dream
seguir cumpliendo, seguir luchando por ese sueño de lograr algo, pero mientras tanto seguí con ese sueño
跟随 跟随
to follow to follow
de seguir de seguir
你继续这样做，因为有时你会遇到一个掉落的情况，因为它们并不都是铁，而且它们并不总是在那里。
You continue with that because sometimes you have one that falls because they are not all iron and they are not always going to be there.
uno sigue por eso porque a veces tenés alguno que cae porque no son todo de fierro y no se van a estar siempre ahí
因为这很难，但是然后...
because it's difficult, but then...
porque es difícil, pero después...
也许一周过去了，我妈妈又说，是的，儿子，你看到了，你回来了，你进了一个球，你必须继续前进，我没有倒下。
Maybe a week goes by and my mother said again, yes son, you saw, you came back, you scored a goal, you have to keep going, I didn't go down.
Capaz que pasa una semana y mi vieja volvió a decir, sí hijo, viste, volviste, hiciste un gol, tenés que seguir, no bajé.
就像这样，在一天结束的时候，家人是永远存在的人，并且会一直支持你的人。
It is like that, at the end of the day the family is the one that is always there and the one that will support you at all times.
Es así, al fin y al cabo la familia es la que siempre está y la que te va a bancar en todos los momentos.
这很棒，因为例子就是你，即使你不愿意，人们也会听你说，看看你是否可以。
It's great because the examples are you, even if you don't want to, people listen to you and say, look if you could.
es buenísimo porque los ejemplos son ustedes aunque no quieran la gente los escucha y dice mira si pudo
也许我也可以，这就是为什么重要的是我们讲述它，而谁生活它是另一件事。
Maybe I can too, that's why it's very important that one thing is that we tell it and another thing is that who lives it.
puede ser que yo pueda también por eso es muy importante una cosa que lo contemos nosotros y otra cosa quien lo vive
在某种程度上，家庭是你的支持。
and in some way the family was your support.
y de alguna manera la familia fue tu sostén.
我想到了另一方面，蔬菜家庭也必须继续下去，我们必须继续解决其他问题、其他情况。
I think about the one on the other side, that the vegetable families also have to continue, we have to continue with other problems, with other circumstances.
Yo pienso en el que está del otro lado, que también las familias de vegetales hay que seguir, hay que seguir con otros problemas, con otras circunstancias.
带着这种意志，带着这种从一切事物中显现出来的信念来听你讲话真是太好了
and it is good to listen to you with this will, with this conviction that appeared from everything
y está bueno escucharte a vos con esta voluntad, con esta convicción que apareció a partir de todo
因为在到达这个地方的过程中发生了很多事情，你可以解释一下。
because a lot of things happened in the middle to get to this place and you can explain it.
porque en el medio pasaron un montón de cosas para poder llegar a este lugar y vos lo podés explicar.
另外就是你的家人对你的干扰程度如何，这个也很重要。
The other is what degree of interference your family has, which is very important.
la otra es que grado recién lo venías explicando de injerencia tiene tu familia que es muy importante
在你职业生涯的最后一部分，你会听他们的意见还是你的头脑决定了这一点？
For the final part of your career, do you listen to them or is your head the one that defines that?
¿Para la parte final de tu carrera los escuchas a ellos o tu cabeza es la que define eso?
不，我认为是一个人的头。
No, I think one's head.
No, creo que la cabeza de uno.
一个人的头。
One's head.
La cabeza de uno.
我觉得家人也可以...
I think family can also...
Creo que la familia también puede...
发表你的意见或者你可以看到一些事情，但最终......
give your opinion or you can see things, but in the end...
opinar o puede ver cosas, pero al final...
比赛的最终结果就是决定性的结果。
The end of the race is one that ends up deciding.
El final de la carrera es uno que termina decidiendo.
举个例子，以防万一，对吧？
Just in case, for example, right?
por si fuese por por ejemplo ¿No?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
如果是为了我的妻子
In case it was for my wife
Por si fuese por por mi mujer
因为今天我要继续留在国家队，我不想让我离开，她告诉我，你是最好的
because today I would continue in the national team, I didn't want me to leave, she told me, you are in the best
porque hoy seguiría en la selección, no no quería que deje, ella me decía, estás en el mejor
我告诉他，我真的感觉到我的内心......
And I told him, I honestly feel inside me...
Y yo le dije, sinceramente siento dentro de mí...
就是那一刻。
that is the moment.
que es el momento.
我不知道为什么，但我觉得是时候退出了。
I don't know why, but I feel like it's time to step aside.
No sé por qué, pero siento que es el momento de dar un paso al costado
并让男孩们
and let the boys
y dejar a los chicos que
达到一个新的
to reach a new
para llegar a a un nuevo
我不知道，我就是这么感觉的，但也许如果我听过的话......
I don't know, I felt it that way, but maybe if I had listened...
No sé, lo sentí de esa manera, pero si capaz que si yo hubiese escuchado...
致我的家人或我能继续留在国家队的妻子
to my family or my capable wife who would have continued in the national team
a mi familia o a mi mujer capaz que hubiese seguido en la selección
但我觉得是时候了，是时候把这一步放在一边了。
But I felt that it was time, that it was time to take that step aside.
pero yo sentí que era el momento, que ya era el momento de dar ese paso al costado.
因为？
Because?
¿Por qué?
为什么
Why
Porque
他也赢得了一切。
He had also earned everything.
también se lo había ganado todo.
我想现在是新孩子们开始的时候了……
And I think it was time for the new kids to start...
Y creo que era el momento de los chicos nuevos de que empiecen a...
因为之后就很难达到
because afterwards it is difficult to reach a
porque después es difícil llegar a un
布埃纳诺特或任何年轻人都有
that Buenanotte or that any of the young people have
que Buenanotte o que cualquiera de los jóvenes tengan
仅预选赛或预选赛分钟并进入世界杯
of qualifying only or minutes of qualifying and reach a world cup
de eliminatoria solamente o minutos de eliminatoria y lleguen a un mundial
参加世界杯和为俱乐部效力不一样，这是完全不同的，它们是两件事
Playing a World Cup is not the same as playing for your club, it is completely different, they are two things
no es lo mismo jugar un Mundial que jugar en tu club, es completamente diferente, son dos cosas
两个不同的世界，因为压力，因为我们的生活，因为一切。
two different worlds, because of pressure, because of what we live, because of everything.
dos mundos diferentes, por presión, por lo que se vive, por todo.
在国家队参加更多比赛会给你多一点支持，多一点支持......
Having more matches in the national team gives you a little more support, a little more support to...
Ya tener más partido en la selección te da un poco más de respaldo, un poco más de espalda para...
面对世界杯，然后是美洲杯
face a world cup, a cup america then
afrontar un mundial una copa américa entonces
我相信，我当时就这么想，现在仍然在想，因为……
I believe and I thought at that moment and I still think about it because...
Creo y pensé en ese momento y lo sigo pensando porque...
这就是为什么我决定是时候离开了。
That's why I made the decision that it was time to leave.
Por eso tomé la decisión de que era el momento de dejar.
所以最后...
So in the end...
Entonces al final...
一个人的头或一个人的身体在说就这样了，就这么远了，不会再走得更远了。
One's head or one's body is when it says that's it, it's this far and it doesn't go any further.
La cabeza de uno o el cuerpo de uno es cuando dice ya está, es hasta acá y no va más.
你知道我听你说话的同时，它也在我身上产生了反思，我的意思是，你甚至有时间考虑别人。
You know that I listen to you and at the same time it generates reflection in me, I mean, you even had time to think about others.
Vos sabés que te escucho y a la vez me genera una reflexión, digo, hasta tuviste tiempo de pensar en los otros.
因为这不是你的决定，请好好思考，直到这里说，因为这是电影的一个精彩的结尾
because it was not your decision and think well until here say because it is a spectacular wonderful closing of the film
porque no fue tu decisión y pensar bueno hasta acá di porque es un cierre de película maravilloso espectacular
塞拉，这是点睛之笔，但你还想到了男孩们积累经验，这说明了你的人品。
Sierra, it's a finishing touch, but you even thought about the boys accumulating experience, that speaks of your human quality.
Sierra, es un broche de oro, sino que hasta pensaste en que los chicos acumulen experiencia, eso habla de tu calidad humana.
你的支持精神
of your supportive spirit
de tu espíritu solidario
我从来没有想过我的电影会如何结束。
I never thought about how my film would end.
Jamás pensé en cómo terminaría mi película.
我本来会输掉美洲杯，而我正在输掉美洲杯，因为决定已经做出了。
I would have lost the Copa América and I was losing the Copa América because the decision had already been made.
La Copa América la hubiese perdido y me iba perdiendo la Copa América porque la decisión ya estaba tomada.
里奥给我球衣的照片是比赛前一天晚上拍的。
The photo with Leo giving me the shirt was from the night before the game.
La foto con Leo regalándome la camiseta era de la noche anterior al partido.
我决定现在退休...
My decision to retire now...
La decisión mía de retirarme ya...
我被带走了。
I was taken.
Estaba tomada.
这部电影的结局可能很糟糕。
The movie could have ended badly.
La película podía haber terminado mal.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
你了解我吗？
Do you understand me?
¿Me entendés?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
我，我的想法一直都在这里
Me, my thought was always here it is
Yo, mi pensamiento siempre fue hasta acá está
我看到新一代的到来，新孩子的到来。
I see a new generation coming, new kids coming.
Veo que viene una nueva generación, vienen nuevos chicos.
是时候给他们空间了，因为最终当有人在那里时......
And it's time to give them space, because in the end when one is there...
Y es el momento de darles espacio, porque al final cuando uno está ahí...
没有人愿意做，也没有人愿意做……
Without wanting to, without one wanting to do it...
Sin querer, sin uno querer hacerlo...
你施加了我必须施加的压力，因为我们打平了
You put that pressure that I have to put it because we are tying
metes esa presión de que lo tengo que poner porque vamos empatando
不，也许如果我放一个
and no and maybe if I put a a
y no y capaz que si pongo a a
因为他已经在决赛中进球了，因为他有太多的进球，你明白我的意思，最后的压力
because he already scored a goal in finals, because he has so many, you understand me, that pressure at the end
porque ya hizo gol en finales, porque tiene tantos me entendés, esa presión al final
在教练的头脑中它也发挥着很多作用，所以
in a coach's head it also plays a lot, so
en la cabeza de un entrenador también juega mucho, entonces
我不希望这样，我希望球队继续获胜，继续成长，继续
I don't want that, I want the team to continue winning, to continue growing, to continue
yo no quiero eso, yo quiero que la selección siga ganando, que siga creciendo, que siga
像他这样向前迈进，那么电影就该结束好还是坏了
being forward like he is doing then it was time for the film to end well or end badly
siendo para adelante como lo está haciendo entonces era el momento la película si terminaba bien o terminaba mal
我在半决赛​​中没有改变你。
I haven't changed you. In the semi-final I said it in the note.
No te he cambiado En la semifinal lo dije en la nota
我要穿过前门，如果我赢得美洲杯，我也会穿过前门，但仅此而已
I'm going through the front door and if I win the Copa América and I'm going through the front door but that's it
me voy por la puerta grande y si gano la Copa América y me voy por el portón pero ya está
如果它已经在那里，那么它就已经实现了。
If it was already there, it had already been achieved.
si ya estaba, ya lo había logrado todo.
这是最后一届美洲杯，世界杯结束后我想参加美洲杯，我说好吧，准备好了，美洲杯就结束了。
It was the last Copa América, I wanted to get to that Copa América, after the World Cup and I said well, ready, the Copa América and it was over.
Era la última Copa América, quise llegar hasta esa Copa América, después del Mundial y dije bueno, listo, la Copa América y se terminó.
就是这样。
And that's it.
Y ya está.
他已经说过了，他已经说得很清楚了。
He had already said it, he had made it clear.
Ya lo había dicho, lo había dejado claro.
喝酒的时候他们问了我几个问题，有时......
During the drink they asked me a couple of questions, sometimes...
Durante la copa me tiraron un par de preguntas, a veces...
男孩们喜欢看看是否……是的，我说是的，就是这样，这是杯子，结束了，就在那里。
The boys like to see if... And yes, I said yes, that's it, it's the cup and it's over and it's over there.
Los chicos como para ver si... Y sí, yo dije sí, ya está, es la copa y se termina y se terminó ahí.
多好啊，因为天使以一种发生在我身上的自然而坚定的信念说出了这句话
how good because angel says it with a conviction with a naturalness that happened to me
qué bueno porque lo dice ángel con una convicción con una naturalidad que a mí me pasó
由头部和每个人他为什么不继续，因为此刻他
by the head and to everyone why doesn't he continue because at the moment he was
por la cabeza y a todos por qué no sigue porque encima en el momento que estaba
我也会说同样的话，我问自己，我也和豪尔赫·利纳说同样的话，
I would have said the same thing, I asked myself, and I say the same as Jorge Lina,
Yo hubiera dicho lo mismo, me preguntaba a mí, y yo digo igual que Jorge Lina,
他必须继续，但很明显，他决定了，而未来你也将决定它。
He has to continue, but it is clear that he decides it and for the future you are going to decide it.
Tiene que seguir, pero está claro que lo decide él y para el futuro vas a decidirlo vos.
是的，完全正确。
Yes, exactly.
Sí, exactamente.
是的，因为头...
Yes, because the head is...
Sí, porque la cabeza es...
就好像一个人内心有一种感觉。
It's like a feeling that one has inside.
Es como una sensación que uno tiene adentro.
感谢上帝，他超越了我，现在，例如，在国家队，所以我知道。
He passed me by, thank God, now, for example, with the national team, so I know.
Él me pasó, gracias a Dios, ya ahora, por ejemplo, con la selección, entonces ya sé.
当一个人说“我已经走到这一步了”是什么感觉？
What feeling is it that one says, I've come this far?
¿Qué sensación es la que uno dice, hasta acá llegué?
这发生在我身上，我说准备好了，就到这里了，当我稍后说的时候
It happened to me and I said ready, it's up to here when I had said it later
me pasó y dije listo es hasta acá cuando lo había dicho después
美洲杯的主席表示，如果他赢得了美洲杯，
of the Copa América that if he won the Copa América, the
de la Copa América que si ganaba la Copa América, la
我说，不，就是这样，美洲杯赢了，就是这样，我要退役了。
I said, no, that's it, the Copa América was won and that's it, I'm retiring.
que dije, no, ya está, la Copa América se ganó y listo, me retiro.
不，我意识到这不是因为那不是感觉。
And no, I realized that it wasn't because it wasn't the sensation.
Y no, me di cuenta que no porque no era la sensación.
最后，世界杯结束后我继续，我说，完成了。
the very final, I continued after the world cup, I said, done.
la finalísima, seguí después del mundial, dije, listo.
世界杯结束了，赢了，就这样，但我还没说完。
The World Cup is over, it was won, that's it, but I didn't finish saying it.
Se terminó el mundial, se ganó, ya está, pero no lo terminaba de decir.
安全的。
safe.
seguro.
然后当我说准备好时
And and then when I said ready
Y y después cuando dije listo
这是最后一届美洲杯，因为它马上就要举行了，而且我仍然有这样的感觉。
It is the last Copa América because it is now right away and I still feel like it is.
es la última Copa América porque ya es ahora enseguida y todavía siento que sí.
是的，但是……
Yes, but...
Sí, pero...
准备好了，美洲杯结束后有一段时间，有几天我说美洲杯结束了，我在家里告诉我的妻子。
Ready, after the Copa América there was a moment, there were a few days when I said the Copa América was over, I told my wife at home.
Listo, después de la Copa América hubo un momento, hubo unos días que dije la Copa América se terminó, se lo dije a mi mujer en casa.
美洲杯已经结束了。
It's the Copa América and it's over.
Es la Copa América y se termina.
我看起来就像，你确定吗？
And I'm looking like, are you sure?
Y me quedo mirando como que, ¿estás seguro?
什么也没有，不。
And nothing, no.
Y nada, no.
在她赢得美洲杯后，她方面没有任何回应。
There was no response from her side after she won the Copa América.
No hubo respuesta al lado de ella después que se ganó la Copa América.
他还告诉我，你确定吗？
He also told me, are you sure?
Me dijo también, ¿estás seguro?
你已经决定了吗？
Have you already decided?
¿Ya lo tenés decidido?
我说，就是这样。
And I said, that's it.
Y dije, ya está.
就在这里，我的头脑、我的身体都在说，就是这样。
It's over here, my head, my body says it and that's it.
Se terminó acá, mi cabeza, mi cuerpo lo dice y listo.
你的女儿们告诉你什么？
And what do your daughters tell you?
¿Y tus hijas qué te dicen?
不，我，我的女儿们，让我的生活幸福的是
No, I, of my daughters, what made my life happy is that
No, yo, de mis hijas, lo que me alegró la vida es que
当她已经有点意识到我是什么的时候，我能够赢得一切。
I was able to win everything while she was already a little aware of what I was.
Pude ganar todo mientras ella estaba ya un poco consciente de lo que yo era.
看看我近年来在国家队取得的一切成就。
and see everything I was able to achieve with the national team in recent years.
y ver todo lo que pude lograr con la selección estos últimos años.
这就是我所剩下的，这是能够拥有的最好的东西。
That's what leaves me, it's the nicest thing to be able to have.
Es lo que me deja a mí, es lo más lindo el poder haber.
成就了一切，她已经看到了，对我来说这就是全部，而她却没有。
achieved everything and that she has seen it, for me that is all, and she has not.
logrado todo y que ella lo hayan visto, para mí ya eso es todo, y ella no.
他们不发表意见，也不告诉我任何事情。
They don't give an opinion, they don't tell me anything.
no opinan, no me dicen nada.
是的，现在国家队比赛的时候就像
Yes, now when the national team plays it's like
Sí, ahora cuando juega la selección es como que
这对他们来说似乎很奇怪，但没什么，当有选择或当......
It seems strange to them, but nothing, when there is a selection or when...
como que les parece raro, pero nada, cuando hay selección o cuando...
我在家里呆了很多天，他们告诉我，他现在就是在那里受伤的，对吗？
I spend many days at home and they tell me, that's where he gets injured now, right?
Paso muchos días en casa y me dicen, ¿ahí se lesiona ahora, no?
因为你在家很多天了。
Because you are home many days.
Porque estás muchos días en casa.
我说，是的。
And I say, yes.
Y le digo, sí.
我告诉他，当然有选择，我有四次，四五天的假期，我在家，你明白吗？
I tell him, there is selection, of course, there I have like four times, four or five days off and I'm at home, you see?
Le digo, ahí selección, claro, ahí tengo como cuatro veces, cuatro o cinco días libres y estoy en casa, ¿viste?
他们也不习惯在家里见到你。
And they're not used to seeing you at home.
Y no están acostumbradas a verte en casa.
对于家庭来说，这也是一个重要的变化。
It is an important change also for the family.
Es un cambio importante también para la familia.
因为有时你当然
because there are times when of course you
porque hay veces que claro vos
有 10 天你没有和家人在一起，然后你回来了，如果你以访客身份玩，你可能会回去两天
and there are 10 days that you are not with the family then you come back and two days and maybe if you played as a visitor you went back then
y son 10 días que no estás con la familia después volvés y dos días y capaz que si jugaste de visitante te fuiste de vuelta entonces
最后他们很难互相理解一点，当然现在当我通过四级时
In the end it is difficult for them to understand each other a little and of course now when I pass four
al final es como es difícil de que ellos se entiendan un poco y claro ahora cuando paso cuatro
五天在
five days in
cinco días en
不，这就是妈妈在家的原因。
No, that's why mom is home.
No, por eso mamá está en casa.
但没什么，对我来说最美丽的事情就是他们很高兴，今天他们很高兴我回家了。
But nothing, for me the most beautiful thing is that they are happy and today they are happy that I am home.
Pero nada, para mí lo más lindo es que ellas estén felices y hoy están felices de que yo esté en casa.
所以现在我很平静。
So that leaves me calm now.
entonces eso ya me deja tranquilo.
安吉尔，如果一位年轻球员走到你面前，对我说你有什么建议，你会对他说什么？
Angel, what would you say to the young player who comes up to you and says what advice do you have for me?
Ángel, ¿qué le dirías al jugador joven que se te acerca y dice qué consejo me das?
对于国家队来说，你刚才提到的这位球员正在走上自己的历史之路。
For the national team, the player you just mentioned a little bit and who is on his way to go through his own history.
para la selección, el jugador estos que recién nombrabas un poco y que va en camino a recorrer su propia historia.
不，这只是...
And no, it's just...
Y no, es que...
他们总是向前迈进，他们不听周围所说的一切。
that they always move forward, that they do not listen to everything that is said around them.
que sigan siempre para adelante, que no escuchen todo lo que se dice alrededor.
让他们梦想，让他们梦想远大，让他们梦想实现自己的目标。
Let them dream, let them dream big, let them dream of wanting to achieve their goals.
que sueñen, que sueñen en grande, que sueñen en querer lograr los objetivos
愿他们永不放弃，愿他们为每一个梦想而奋斗。
May they never give up, may they fight for every dream they have.
que nunca bajen los brazos, que peleen por cada sueño que tienen.
没什么，我认为重要的是总是想更多，这让我
and nothing, I think the important thing is to always think about more, it made me
y nada, creo que lo importante es siempre pensar en más, a mí me hizo
到达我所到达的地方并实现我所取得的成就感谢......
get to where I got and achieve the things I achieved thanks to...
llegar a donde llegué y lograr las cosas que logré gracias a...
在我的脑海里，总是想要更多。
to my head, always wanting more.
a mi cabeza, al querer siempre más.
拥有十个头衔并不断想要达到十一个、十二个等等。
by having ten titles and wanting to go to eleven, twelve and so on constantly.
al tener diez títulos y querer pasar a once, a doce y así constantemente.
这是一份工作，我觉得这一年我的工作做得很好。
It's a job and I feel like I did my job well during the year.
Es un trabajo y yo mi trabajo siento que lo hice bien durante el año.
如果在这一年结束时我举起奖杯，如果没有，我觉得这一年......
If when the year ends I lift the trophy, if not I feel that it was a year that...
si cuando termine el año levanto el trofeo, si no siento que fue un año que...
你可能会学到一些东西，但那是浪费的一年，是你浪费掉的一年，因为你付出了这么多的牺牲却毫无结果，所以......
You may learn things, but it was a wasted year, a year that you threw away because you made so much sacrifice for nothing, so...
que capaz que aprendes cosas, pero fue un año perdido, un año que tirás a la basura porque hiciste tanto sacrificio para nada, entonces...
我认为当今球员和年轻人的目标是始终设定目标。
I think the objective of the player and of the young people today is to always set goals.
el objetivo creo que del jugador y de los jóvenes hoy en día es proponerse siempre objetivos.
我们的目标始终是在这一年结束时取得一些成果。
And the goal is always that finishing the year will achieve something.
Y el objetivo siempre está en que terminar el año logrará algo.
完成这一年并成为最佳助攻手、得分手。
to finish the year and be the top assister, the scorer.
en terminar el año y poder ser el máximo asistidor, el goleador.
总是为你提供一些东西，我认为这是最重要的事情之一......
always to provide you with something, I think it is one of the most important things to...
siempre por proveerte algo, creo que es una de las cosas más importantes para...
为了自己，什么都没有，就是这样，就是想实现……
for oneself and nothing, that's it, it's trying to fulfill...
para uno mismo y nada, es eso, es intentar cumplir...
每一个梦想，都牢记在心，永不放弃。
every dream that one puts in mind and never give up.
cada sueño que uno se pone en mente y nunca bajar los brazos.
别杀我，但你认为自己将来会当教练吗？
Don't kill me, but do you see yourself as a coach in the future?
No me mates, pero te ves entrenador en el futuro?
我正在做课程。
I'm doing the course.
Estoy haciendo el curso.
我正在参加课程，看看以后会发生什么。
I'm taking the course to see what happens later.
Estoy haciendo el curso para ver qué onda más adelante.
不，我说是因为有这种氛围，体育部长，你们是真正的大使，今天的范围又开放了一点。
No, I say because there is the vibe, sports secretary, you are true ambassadors, today the spectrum opened up a little more.
No, digo porque está la onda secretario deportivo, ustedes son verdaderos embajadores, hoy ahí se abrió un poco más el espectro.
这就是我问你的原因。
That's why I asked you.
Por eso te he preguntado.
是的，是的，但我不知道真相。
Yes, yes, but I don't know the truth.
Sí, sí, pero no sé la verdad.
说实话，我也没什么想法。
Honestly, I don't have anything in mind either.
Sinceramente tampoco tengo algo en mente.
这很好，因为他们说你想到的全部是因为你快要离开了
that's good because they say total you have in mind because because you're almost leaving then
eso es bueno porque dicen total tenés en mente porque porque ya estás casi dejando entonces
呃，我在那边很冷静，但是我不会这样做，因为它有它的
eh I'm calm on that side eh but I'm not doing it because it has its
eh estoy tranquilo por ese lado eh pero no lo estoy haciendo porque tiene sus
这也需要几年的时间，而你想把它做好，所以......
It takes years too and you want to do it well, so...
Lleva sus años también y uno lo quiere hacer bien, entonces...
我就是因为这个原因才这样做的，稍后我会看到
I'm doing it for that reason and then I'll see later
lo estoy haciendo por eso y después veré más adelante
我突然想到想成为一名教练。
It crosses my mind to want to be a coach.
se me cruza por la cabeza querer ser entrenador.
我不知道我是否
I don't know if I
no sé si me
一点点
a little what one can
un poco lo que lo que uno puede
玩家，对吧？
player, right?
jugador, ¿no?
这是肾上腺素，因为好吧，你听着，对吧？
It's adrenaline, because well, you listen, right?
Es adrenalina, porque bueno, uno escucha, ¿no?
我从基利、帕布利托和沃尔特那里听到了很多建议。
I heard a lot of advice from Killy, from Pablito, from Walter.
Escuché muchos consejos del Killy, de Pablito, de Walter.
嗯，来自我
eh from me
eh de mi
他们停止了比赛，每个人都会告诉你和你停止比赛时一样的事情。
They stopped playing and everyone tells you the same thing as when you stopped.
dejaron de jugar y todo el mundo te dice lo mismo que cuando dejás.
你会觉得游戏、旅行、……缺乏肾上腺素。
You feel that lack of adrenaline from games, from traveling, from...
Sentís esa falta de adrenalina de los partidos, del viajar, de...
但是好吧，我知道什么，我不知道，每个人都会有自己的事情，我会看看什么时候......
But well, what do I know, I don't know, each one will have their own thing, I'll see when...
Pero bueno, qué sé yo, no sé, cada uno tendrá lo suyo, yo veré cuando...
当我的结束时，我会看到我是什么
when when mine ends and there I will see what is what I
cuando cuando lo lo mío termine y ahí veré que que es lo que se me
我的脑海中闪过了这个念头，然后我就会决定我想去哪里走自己的路，对吗？
It crosses my mind and I will decide where I want to go to make my way, right?
se me cruza por la cabeza y decidiré por dónde quiero ir a hacer mi camino, ¿no?
安赫尔，你刚才谈论的是巴布利托、沃尔特、斯卡罗尼。
Ángel, you were just talking about Pablito, Walter, Scaloni.
Ángel, recién hablabas de Pablito, de Walter, de Scaloni.
我问你，我们从外面说他是一个好经理
I ask you, we from the outside say that he is a good manager
Te pregunto, nosotros de afuera decimos que es un buen gestionador
他们是搞战术的，你怎么定义教练组的梯队和一把手？
They work on tactics, how do you define the coaching staff with echelon and at the head?
trabajan lo táctico, ¿cómo lo definís vos al cuerpo técnico con escalón y a la cabeza?
对我来说，它们是完整的。
For me they are complete.
Para mí son completos.
这是一个完整的教练组。
It's a complete coaching staff.
Es un cuerpo técnico completo.
因为他们在战术上下了很多功夫
because they work a lot on tactics
porque trabajan mucho en lo que es el táctico
防守，进攻。
to defend, to attack.
para defender, para atacar.
你有沃尔特和鼠标的球部分。
You have the ball part with Walter, with the mouse.
Tenés la parte de pelota parada con Walter, con el ratón.
你有巴勃罗的建议，他聊了多少……
You have Pablo's advice, how much he talks to...
Tenés los consejos de Pablo, lo mucho que habla con...
同步并集结队伍，看如何进攻。
with a step and to assemble the team, to see how to attack.
con escalón y para armar el equipo, para ver cómo atacar.
嘿，你拥有一切 假设你拥有一切
hey you have everything let's say you have everything
eh tenés todo digamos tenés todo
你拥有一切，因为他们也是球员，所以他们知道球员喜欢什么，不喜欢什么。
You have everything because they were also players so they know what the player likes, what he doesn't like.
tenés todo porque también fueron jugadores entonces saben lo que le gusta al jugador, lo que no le gusta
什么可以困扰玩家？
What can bother the player?
¿Qué es lo que lo puede molestar al jugador?
什么不困扰你？
What doesn't bother you?
¿Qué es lo que no le molesta?
某天休息，集中注意力。
some day off, the concentrations.
algún día libre, las concentraciones.
或食物或事物，然后...
or the foods or the things, then...
o las comidas o las cosas, entonces...
他们拥有这一切，这就是为什么对我来说这是一个完整的教练组，因为它拥有一切。
They have all that and that is why for me it is a coaching staff that is complete because it has everything.
tienen todo eso y por eso para mi es un cuerpo técnico que es completo porque tiene todo
我想最终什么也没有……
And nothing, I think in the end...
Y nada, creo que al final...
人们不能谈论运气或任何东西，因为如果你赢得一个奖杯，你可能很幸运，但如果你赢得三座或四座奖杯，你就已经很幸运了。
One cannot talk about luck or anything because you can be lucky if you win one trophy but if you win three or four you are already lucky.
uno no puede hablar de ni de suerte ni de nada porque podes tener suerte si ganas un trofeo pero si ganas tres o cuatro ya
这不再是运气和什么，我认为对我来说这是一个完美的教练组。
It's no longer luck and nothing, I think that for me it is a perfect coaching staff.
ya no es suerte y nada, creo que para mi es un cuerpo técnico perfecto.
所以我希望他们继续
so I hope they continue
entonces ojalá que sigan
也决定想要
also decides to want
también decide querer
选择是主要的而且很好，但是同时
the selection is main and and good, but but while
la selección es principal y y bueno, pero pero mientras
事情会继续顺利进行，他们有很好的眼光......
things are going to continue running well and they have a good eye for...
las cosas van a seguir corriendo bien y tienen un buen ojo para...
去见玩家，因为很多玩家
to see players because many players
para ver jugadores porque muchos jugadores
今天，他们是世界冠军，很多。
Today they are world champions, many.
hoy en día son campeones del mundo, muchos.
几乎没有人不认识他们，或者他们没有被命名，他们开始带来
almost no one did not know them or they were not named and they began to bring
casi o casi nadie no los conocían o no eran nombrados y ellos empezaron a traer
吸引他们，就像什么都没发生一样，最终他们组建了一个壮观的团体。
attract them as if nothing had happened and in the end they ended up putting together a spectacular group.
atraerlos como si nada y al final terminaron armando un grupo espectacular.
这就是我要告诉你的，你看到的这一代人在未来会拥有教练的愿景
That's what I was going to tell you, this generation you see in the future with that vision of coaches of
eso te iba a decir esta generación la ves en el futuro con con esa visión de entrenadores de
然后生活就会像发生在你身上一样对待你，但你注意到这个群体是由……组成的。
Then life takes you as it will happen to you, but you notice that this group that was put together with...
después la vida te va llevando como te va a pasar a vos pero los notas que este grupo que se armó con...
在卡塔尔，当轮到他们作为职业球员出去时，他们可以当教练。
with Qatar they can be coaches when it is their turn to go out as professional players.
con Qatar puedan ser entrenadores cuando les toque salir como jugadores profesionales.
我不知道，因为后来每个人也住在这里、那里……
And I don't know, because later each one also lives here, there...
Y no sé, porque después cada uno también vive acá, allá...
每个人都有自己的生活
everyone has their life
cada uno tiene tiene su vida
而且不知道以后能不能整合起来，确实是很不错的东西。
and I don't know if it can be put together afterwards, it's really something nice.
y no sé si después se puede armar, es algo lindo la verdad.
因为教练组里交错的卡尔莫是一件非常好的事情，不仅是
because the staggered carmo in that coaching staff is something it is something very nice to have not only
porque lo carmo escalónico en ese cuerpo técnico es algo es algo muy lindo tener no solamente
他们是同伴，不再是友谊，而且他们都处于同一个......
that they were companions and no longer a friendship and they were all in the same...
que fueron compañeros y no ya una amistad y estar todos en el mismo...
教练组，最重要的是，双方都有一个教练组，并且能够将一些很棒的东西组合在一起。
coaching staff and on top of that having one on each side and being able to put together something so nice.
cuerpo técnico y encima tener uno de cada lado y poder armar algo tan lindo.
那就太好了，但很高兴看到
It would be good but then it's good to see
sería bueno pero bueno después es ver
到时候，大家都在哪里，看看能不能，不能的话，就家人吧。
at the time, where everyone is, let's see if it's possible, if not, the family.
en su momento, dónde está cada uno, a ver si se puede, si no, la familia.
这也是一件容易的事情。
It's also something easy.
también es algo fácil.
他是与狮子座同时代的人，很少有其他人是这样的，因为
He has been a contemporary of Leo like few others because
ha sido contemporáneo de Leo como pocos porque
当他们还是个孩子的时候，他们就开始遵循你所说的关于梦想的道路，而今天看来是如此自然，因为我们从另一个地方看到了它。
As a child they began to follow the path of what you were talking about about dreams and that today seems so natural because we see it from another place.
de chiquito empezaron a recorrer el camino de esto de lo que hablabas de los sueños y que hoy parece tan natural porque nosotros lo vemos de otro lugar
酒吧。
bar.
当然可以，告诉我一些你不总是被问到的关于狮子座的事情。
Definitely and tell me something you haven't always been asked about Leo.
definitivamente y contame como algo que no se te han preguntado siempre sobre leo
但你可以与人们分享一些东西。
but something you can share with people.
pero algo que puedas compartir con la gente.
不，我说的都是关于利奥的事。
No, I said it all about Leo.
No, de Leo lo dije todo.
为我...
For me...
Para mí...
这是我职业生涯中发生的最好的事情。
It was the best thing that happened to me in my career.
Fue lo mejor que me pasó en mi carrera.
当然，就像其他人一样，这是和迭戈一起踢球的结果。
Surely, like for others, it was having played with Diego.
Seguramente como para otros fue haber jugado con Diego.
有这样的可能性就是最好的
It is the best to have that possibility
es lo máximo el tener esa posibilidad
经过这么多年建立了友谊。
and after so many years creating a friendship.
y de tantos años encima crear una amistad.
这就是一切。
It's everything.
Lo es todo.
矮人是...
The dwarf is...
El enano es...
他在场上和场下都表现出色，所以...
He's as phenomenal on the court as he is off the court, so...
es fenomenal dentro de la cancha como es fuera de la cancha, entonces...
我有过这样的机会并且我告诉了他
I had that chance and I told him so
tuve esa posibilidad y se lo dije
我在巴黎圣日耳曼的最后一场比赛结束后拥抱他时告诉了他。
I told him after my last game at Paris Saint Germain when I hugged him.
Se lo dije después del último partido mío en el Paris Saint Germain cuando lo abracé.
在更衣室里，我说谢谢你让我与你分享这一年，因为……
in the locker room and I said thank you for letting me share this year with you because...
en el vestuario y le dije gracias por dejarme compartir este año con vos porque...
因为当巴萨的一切都发生在利亚身上时，他来到巴黎让我们大吃一惊。
Because when everything about Barça happened with Lea, we blew his mind with him coming to Paris.
Porque cuando pasó todo lo del Barça con Lea le volamos la cabeza con que venga a París.
因为我想和他一起打球，我曾经有过这样的机会
Because I wanted to play with him, I once had that chance to be able to
porque yo deseaba jugar con él tuve esa chance alguna vez de poder
能够去巴萨。
to be able to go to Barça.
de poder ir al Barça.
但这从未实现，事情总是发生，总是有事情，但最终它们从未......
but that never materialized, that things always happened, there were always things and in the end they never...
pero que nunca se concretó, que siempre pasaron cosas, siempre hubo cosas y al final nunca...
那从未发生过，但我只想和他一起玩，能够......
That never happened, but all I wanted was to play with him, to be able to...
Nunca se dio eso, pero yo lo único que quería era jugar con él, poder...
和他一起生活一年，看看...
live with him for a year and see...
vivir con él durante un año y ver...
他所做的，因为你可以在训练、比赛中看到它，但是......
what he does, because you see it in training, in games, but...
lo que hace, porque vos lo ves en los entrenamientos, en los partidos, pero...
但我每次看到选择都是10天，每天都有……
but every time I see in the selection it is 10 days and having it every day is...
pero cada vez que veo en la selección son 10 días y tenerlo todos los días es...
这和我们当年在巴黎吃过的完全不同。
It is completely different and having had it that year in Paris with us.
es completamente diferente y haberlo tenido ese año en París con nosotros.
对我来说，这是画龙点睛，感谢上帝，一切都赢了。
For me it was the finishing touch, then thank God everything was won that was won.
Para mí era el broche de oro, después gracias a Dios se ganó todo lo que se ganó.
在国家队，但对我来说，和他在俱乐部一起度过了一年是唯一的事情......
with the national team, but for me having spent a year with him in a club was the only thing that...
con la selección, pero para mí haber estado un año con él en un club era lo único que...
我失踪了，我想要，而且我能够做到，所以，呃，什么都没有。
that I was missing and wanted and I was able to do it, so, eh, nothing.
que me faltaba y deseaba y lo pude hacer, así que, eh, nada.
作为一名足球运动员，拥有这种可能性是发生在我身上的最好的事情。
Having had that possibility is the best thing that happened to me as a footballer.
El haber tenido esa posibilidad es lo mejor que me pasó futbolísticamente.
就在通过之后
and just after passing a
y recién al pasar también una
从根本上来说，是为了让人们能够享受到，有所得才有回报。
fundamentally so that people can enjoy it, one realizes the return when there is
fundamentalmente para que lo disfrute la gente, la devolución uno se da cuenta cuando hay
一定的安慰，我感谢你的部分时间，我总是告诉你。
certain comfort and I thank you for part of the time and I always tell you that.
cierta comodidad y te agradezco parte del tiempo y te lo digo siempre.
关于迭戈的一些事情，因为当你经过时，你说了一些关于迭戈的短语。
something about Diego because when you passed by you said some phrase about Diego.
algo de Diego porque al pasar decías alguna frase de Diego.
抱歉我没听到你的声音。
Sorry I didn't hear you.
Perdón no te escuché.
关于马拉多纳，关于马拉多纳，我告诉过你了。
About Maradona, about Maradona I told you.
De Maradona, de Maradona te decía.
关于迭戈，你还记得什么？
What do you remember about Diego?
¿Qué recordás de Diego?
对我来说这是...
For me it is...
Para mí es...
他是上帝，他就像我的第二个父亲，他就是一切。
He's God, he's like he's my second dad, he's everything.
Es Dios, es como si fuese mi segundo papá, lo es todo.
它让我度过了最糟糕的时期。
It got me through the worst.
Me arrancó en las peores.
他总是相信我，他总是支持我，他总是在那里给我建议。
He always believed in me, he always supported me, he was always there to give me advice.
Siempre creyó en mí, siempre me bancó, siempre estuvo ahí para darme un consejo.
晚上他来到房间时发生的轶事
the anecdotes with him from when he came to the room at night
las anécdotas con él de cuando venía a la habitación a la noche
凌晨十二点或一点的时候，我会放下这篇文章并开始聊天。
At twelve or one in the morning I would drop the piece and start chatting.
a las doce o a las una de la mañana que me caía la pieza y se me ponía a charlar.
老实说，这就是为什么我在美洲杯决赛之前告诉你的
Honestly, that's why I told you before the Copa América final
Sinceramente, por eso te dije antes de la final de la Copa América
我请求他并告诉他帮我一把，我知道他会和我们在一起，他会在那里。
I asked him and told him to give me a hand, that I knew he was going to be with us, that he was going to be there.
Le pedí a él y le dije que me dé una mano, que sabía que iba a estar con nosotros, que iba a estar ahí.
没什么，我进球了，比赛结束了。
And nothing, I scored the goal and finished.
Y nada, hice el gol y terminé.
凭借这个进球，我们取得了胜利。
It was won with that goal.
Se ganó con ese gol.
从那时起，我就好像拥有了它……
And from then on it's like I had it as if it were...
Y a partir de ahí es como que lo tuve como si fuese...
天哪，后来在决赛中我也做到了。
a god, later in the final I did it too.
un dios, después en la finalísima también lo hice.
在世界决赛中我也问过他，那里有一个视频
In the world final I also asked him and well there is a video there
en la final del mundo también se lo pedí y bueno hay un hay un video ahí
他正在约会，我什至没有意识到我已经感谢了他。
that he was dating, that I didn't even realize that I had thanked him.
que estuvo saliendo, que ni yo me di cuenta que le había agradecido a él.
没什么，事实就是如此。
And nothing, the truth is that it honestly is.
Y nada, la verdad que sinceramente lo es.
这对我来说就是一切，因为...
It's everything to me because...
Lo es todo para mí porque...
因为他在我困难的时候一直在我身边支持我，我一直感受到那种爱。
because he was there in the hard times and supported me and I always felt that love.
porque estuvo en los momentos duros y me bancó y siempre sentí ese cariño.
那个爸爸对儿子的感情不一样，有我
That dad's affection for a son was different, it had me
diferente ese cariño de de papá hacia un hijo eh me tuvo
我一直很感激，直到今天，当我有时与......
and I was always grateful until today when I sometimes talk to...
y siempre estuve agradecido hasta el día de hoy cuando a veces hablo con...
他和克劳迪娅或我的格尔穆的女儿们说，他相处得很好，总是……
With Claudia or my Germu he talks to the daughters that he gets along very well, always...
con Claudia o mi germu habla con las hijas que se lleva muy bien, siempre...
总是什么都没有，我们记得那些时刻，克劳迪娅总是告诉我同样的事情，她爱我，就像我是儿子一样。
Always nothing, we remember those moments and Claudia always tells me the same thing, that she loved me as if I were a son.
Siempre nada, nos acordamos de esos momentos y Claudia siempre me dice lo mismo, que me quería como si fuese un hijo.
他们不能谈论我，我为自己辩护。
that they couldn't talk about me, that I defended myself.
que no podían hablar de mí, que me defendía.
并且他永远感激他。
And he is eternally grateful to him.
Y es agradecido eternamente a él.
你知道吗，你甚至说了一个非常熟悉的词，la germu？
Do you know that you even said a very familiar term, la germu?
¿Vos sabés que hasta dijiste un término muy del, la germu?
你看，当他说话并提到克劳迪娅时，他非常迭戈。
You saw that he was very Diego when he spoke and referred to Claudia.
Viste que era muy de Diego cuando hablaba y se refería a Claudia.
呃呃迭戈绝对是这样的
eh eh Diego was definitely like that
eh eh Diego era así definitivamente
我离开那个地方，带着永久的钦佩听你说话，因为你谈论别人。
I leave that place and listen to you with permanent admiration because you talk about others.
Me salgo de ese lugar y te escucho con una admiración permanente porque hablas de los demás.
那就是人们不需要谈论自己的时候，因为你已经构建了故事，人们因为你而说话。
and that is when one does not need to be talking about oneself because you have built the story and people speak because of you.
y eso es cuando no necesita uno estar hablando de uno mismo porque vos has construido la historia y por vos habla la gente
关于你的电影、你的故事以及你长大后的想象，我们邀请你，你还记得吗？
about your film, your story and imagine when you grow up and we are inviting you, do you remember?
de tu película, de tu historia y que imaginate cuando seas grande y te estemos invitando, ¿te acordás?
你是怎么跑的，戴着眼镜，已经全灰了，呃，小天使？
How did you do that run and you're wearing glasses, already all gray, eh, little angel?
¿Cómo hiciste esa corrida y vos estés con anteojo, ya todo canoso, eh, angelito?
当……嗯？
What happens when... Huh?
Como pasa cuando... ¿Eh?
你为什么……？
Why do you...?
¿Por qué vos...?
我现在已经白发了！
I'm gray-haired now!
¡Canoso ya estoy!
不，但是……！
No, but...!
¡No, pero...!
他们只是把眼镜递给我！
They just hand me the glasses!
¡Me pasan los anteojos nomás!
但在某种程度上，你会被邀请到所有的地方，因为你和其他人一样登上了阿根廷足球的最大版面
but in some way you are going to be invited to all the places because you are on the biggest page of Argentine football like everyone else
pero de alguna manera vas a estar invitado a todos los lugares porque estés en la página más grande del fútbol argentino como todos
给那些
to those
a aquellos
当我们被邀请从一个很小的地方询问时，我觉得有点认同你经常说的一句话
I feel a little identified with a phrase that you say all the time when we are invited from a very small place to ask
un poco me siento identificado con una frase que decís todo el tiempo que a mí cuando nos invitan de un lugar muy chiquito a preguntar
我不想陷入其中，因为我不感兴趣，因为我说他们是妈妈和爸爸，我强迫你说你更爱谁，妈妈还是爸爸。
I don't want to fall into that because I'm not interested and because I say they are mom and dad, I force you to say who you love more, mom or dad.
no quiero caer en eso porque no me interesa y porque digo son mamá y papá yo a vos te obligo a decir a quién querés más a mamá o a papá
我听你这么说过，这是我最喜欢的一句话
and I have heard you say it and that is my favorite phrase
y te lo he escuchado decir y esa es mi frase de cabecera
因为我有这样的感觉，他们非常强大，而且一直
because I feel like that, they are very strong and one has been
porque lo siento así, son muy fuertes y uno ha sido
我永远感激他，因为他高高举起了所有阿根廷人的旗帜。
contemporary of it and is eternally grateful to him because he has raised the flag of all Argentines very high.
contemporáneo de ello y le está eternamente agradecido porque ha levantado muy alto la bandera de todos los argentinos.
就像你和所有男孩所做的那样，我现在回到我想请你完成的其他事情。
Just like you and all the boys did, I return to something else that I want to ask you now to finish.
al igual que lo hiciste vos y todos los chicos vuelvo a otra cosa que te quiero preguntar ya para ir terminando
你在皇马和曼彻斯特踢过哪位鼹鼠球员，而我们才刚刚开始？
What mole player did you play for Real Madrid and Manchester and we just started at the beginning?
¿Qué jugador de topos jugaste en el Real Madrid y Manchester y empezamos recién recorríamos al comienzo?
哪些球员让你感到惊讶？
Which players have surprised you?
¿Qué jugadores te han sorprendido?
你们三四岁的时候是说实话的吗？
Are you 3 or 4 who tell the truth?
¿Sos 3 o 4 que decís la verdad?
除去梅西和马拉多纳，谁让你惊讶这些球员做了其他事情？
Taking out Messi and Maradona, who have surprised you that these players did something else?
sacando a Messi y a Maradona, ¿quiénes te han sorprendido que si estos jugadores hacían otra cosa?
嗯，我不知道，事实是...
Well, I don't know, the truth is...
Bueno, no sé, la verdad que...
这很困难，因为你可以处理的玩家数量很多。
which is difficult because of the number of players you can handle.
que es difícil por la cantidad de jugadores que puede con uno.
分享，但老实说，什么也没有……
share, but nothing, honestly...
compartir, pero nada, sinceramente...
如果我必须告诉你一些的话，那是因为……
If I have to tell you some it is because...
Si te tengo que decir algunos es por...
这是西布拉，因为他有多大，因为他有多强壮。
It's Cibra, because of how big he was, because of how strong he was.
es Cibra, por lo grandote que era, por lo fuerte que era.
他必须移动敏捷，轻松……
the agility he had to move, the ease of...
la agilidad que tenía para moverse, la facilidad para...
做你说的两米不正常的事情以及测量的事情
to do things that you say is not normal for two meters and something that measured
para hacer cosas que vos decís no es normal por dos metros y algo que medía
因为他的体型太大了，所以他所做的事情和所做的事情，对于他来说是不可能的。
Because of how big he was, it was impossible for him to do the things he did and did.
por lo grandote que era, era imposible que haga las cosas que hacía y las hacía.
嗯，那就是其中一名球员
eh so that's that that would be one of the players
eh así que es es ese sería uno de de los jugadores
后来，说实话，没什么奇怪的，不，因为……
Afterwards, honestly, nothing surprising, no, because...
Después, nada, sinceramente, de sorprender, no, porque...
感谢上帝，我有机会和最好的球员一起踢球。
Thank God I had that chance to play with the best.
Gracias a Dios tuve esa posibilidad de jugar con los mejores.
感谢上帝，我很幸运能和玩PlayStation的鲁尼一起踢球
Thank God I was lucky enough to play with Rooney who played Playstation
gracias a Dios tuve esa suerte de jugar con Rooney que jugaba a la Playstation
24 岁、快 25 岁的时候，我突然来到了曼彻斯特，和他一起踢球
and out of nowhere I was in Manchester at 24 almost 25 years old playing with him
y de la nada estaba en Manchester con 24 casi 25 años jugando con él
没什么，事实是，这些年对我来说是难忘的，因为有可能
And nothing, the truth is that they were unforgettable years for me because having that possibility of having
Y nada, la verdad que fueron años inolvidables para mí porque tener esa posibilidad de haber
前几天我也说过，他们让我做一个十一，不可能做一个十一
The other day I had also said it they asked me to make an eleven, it is impossible to make an eleven
el otro día también lo lo había dicho me pidieron para hacer un once es imposible hacer un once
这是不可能的，我不能，我把谁排除在外是一回事。
It's impossible, I can't, who am I leaving out? It's one thing.
es imposible no puedo a quien dejo afuera es una cosa
不合逻辑吧？
Illogically, right?
ilógicamente, ¿no?
没什么诚实的，事实是我不能告诉你，我不能告诉你，因为我有机会和......
Nothing honest, the truth is that I can't tell you, I can't tell you because I had that chance to play with...
Nada sincera, la verdad que no puedo decirte, no puedo decirte porque tuve esa posibilidad de jugar con...
与最好的人一起，他们都让我感到惊讶，因为他们都做了我不敢相信的事情
with the best and they all surprised me because they all did things that I couldn't believe
con los mejores y todos me sorprendieron porque todos hacían cosas que no lo podía creer
好吧，明天我会回到两年前的事情。
Well, tomorrow I'll go back to the two-year thing.
Bueno, mañana vuelvo a lo de los dos años.
当他把它拿出来时告诉我。
Tell me the divu when he takes it out.
Contámela el divu cuando se la saca.
当他用脚盖住球时。
when he covers the ball with his foot.
cuando tapa la pelota con el pie.
你把自己定位在哪里？
Where do you locate yourself?
¿Dónde tú ubicas vos?
你还记得那一刻你在哪里吗？
Do you remember where you were at that moment?
¿Te acordás dónde estabas en ese momento?
球场上哪里？
Where on the court?
¿En qué lugar de la cancha?
是的，他坐在他旁边，他坐在罗德里旁边。
Yes, he was sitting next to him, he was sitting next to Rodri.
Sí, estaba sentado al lado, estaba sentado al lado de Rodri.
好的。
GOOD.
Bien.
感谢上帝，我没有看到她，因为他们停下来了
And thank God I didn't see her because how they stopped
Y gracias a Dios que no la vi porque como se pararon
大家，我太紧张了，我坐着，我没有看到，当球被拒绝时，我看到了，但是当然
everyone I was so nervous that I was sitting I didn't see I saw when the ball was rejected but of course
todos yo estaba tan nervioso que estaba sentado no vi vi cuando la pelota se rechazó pero claro
人们知道发生了一些非常强烈的事情，但在那一刻
the murmur of the people was known that something very strong had happened but at that moment
el murmullo de la gente era sabido que había pasado algo fuertísimo pero en ese momento
不！
¡No!
我向我的女儿们发誓，我没有看到迭戈什么时候带她出去，因为她们都站在我面前，我没有看到发生了什么。
I swear on my daughters, I didn't see when Diego took her out, because they all stood in front of me and I didn't see what had happened.
Te juro por mis hijas, no vi cuando el Diego la saca, porque se pararon todos adelante mío y no vi lo que había pasado.
但当听到那样的“buuuu”时，什么也没有……
But nothing, when the buuuu was heard like that...
Pero nada, cuando se escuchó el buuuu así...
他坐在罗德里旁边，就好像喉咙里有一个肿块随时会在空气中爆炸一样。
It's like he had a lump in his throat that would explode through the air at any moment. He was sitting next to Rodri.
es como que tenía el nudo en la garganta que en cualquier momento explotaba por el aire estaba sentado al lado de Rodri
我不知道罗德里是否看到了她，因为他也坐在我旁边，他甚至没有像我一样站起来。
I don't know if Rodri saw her because he was sitting next to me too, he didn't even manage to stand up like me.
que no sé si Rodri la vio porque estaba sentado al lado mío también, ni siquiera alcanzó a pararse igual que yo.
但没什么，事实是……
But nothing, the truth is...
Pero nada, la verdad que...
我们能成为冠军也多亏了他。
That we were champions also thanks to him.
Que fuimos campeones también gracias a él.
我总是说同样的话，对吗？
I always said the same thing, right?
Yo siempre dije lo mismo, ¿no?
你可以拥有最好的，但是...
You can have the best, but...
Podés tener los mejores, pero...
但如果在你需要拯救的时刻，你的拱门中没有人来拯救你……
But if you don't have someone in your arch to save you in those moments when you need to be saved...
Pero si no tenés en el arco a alguien que te salve en esos momentos que necesita que te salven...
这是不可能的，感谢上帝，我们有当时出现的图画。
It is impossible and, thank God, we had the Drawing that appeared at that time.
es imposible y nosotros gracias a Dios tuvimos al Dibu que apareció en esos momentos.
给我介绍一下国家队球员的演变，除了天赋之外，你还看中了他们什么？
Give me an evolution of the national team players, besides having talent, what else did you see in them?
Dame una evolución de los jugadores de la selección, que además de tener talento, ¿qué otra cosa les veías?
当你们在日常生活中、在私下里时，对方的人会说这是一个很棒的团队。
When you were on a day-to-day basis, in privacy, the person on the other side says it was a great team.
cuando estabas en el día a día, en la intimidad, el que está del otro lado dice era un equipazo.
我有一位教练或教练组，他们能够在正确的时间安排球员进行微调。
I had a coach or a coaching staff that had the fine tuning of putting the players at the right time.
Tenía un entrenador o un cuerpo técnico que tenía la sintonía fina de poner a los jugadores en el momento que correspondía.
里面的人是你吗？
You who were inside?
¿Vos que estabas adentro?
除了打球好之外，他们还有什么？
What did they have besides playing ball well?
¿Qué tenían además de jugar bien a la pelota?
团体。
The group.
El grupo.
该团体非常壮观。
The group was spectacular.
El grupo era espectacular.
我相信，当外表一切顺利时，一切都会更容易反映在内心。
I believe that when things go well on the outside, everything is reflected much easier inside.
Yo creo que cuando las cosas van bien fuera adentro se refleja mucho más fácil todo.
还有那个团体，那个工会。
and that group that there was, the union that there was.
y ese grupo que había, la unión que había.
我告诉很多男孩，我们喝马黛茶时总是在聊天等等。
I told many of the boys that we are always chatting when we are drinking mate and all that.
a muchos de los chicos les dije que siempre charlando cuando estamos tomando mate y todo eso
我告诉他2014年的气氛让我出现了很多，...
I told him that the atmosphere of 2014 made me appear a lot, the...
le decía que me hacía aparecer mucho el de 2014 el ambiente, la...
一切涉及...
Everything that entails...
Todo lo que conlleva...
世界杯或者美洲杯，必须保持这么长时间的良好关系，被关起来。
a World Cup or a Copa América, having to have a good relationship for so long, being locked up.
un mundial o una Copa América, el tener que tener una buena relación durante tanto tiempo, el estar encerrado.
这让我想起了很多2014年的事情
It reminded me a lot of 2014 and
me hacía acordar mucho al 2014 y
2014 年，甜点中缺少了草莓，只是因为……
And in 2014 the strawberry was missing for dessert just because after...
Y en 2014 faltó la frutilla de postre nada más porque después...
我们也经历了一场精彩的世界杯，但我们错过了决赛，但是……
We had also had a great World Cup and we missed the finale, but...
Habíamos hecho también un gran mundial y nos faltó el final, pero...
但没什么，我认为当你有一个这样的团队时，一切都会朝着同一个方向发展，那......
But nothing, I think that when you have a group like that, that pulls everything in the same direction, that...
Pero nada, creo que cuando tenés un grupo así, que tiran todo para el mismo lado, que...
一切都很顺利，每个人都知道自己扮演的角色，你也知道
that everything is going well, that everyone knows the role they play, that you also know that
que va todo bien, que todos saben el rol que cumplen, que también sabes que
不，我不会参加比赛，因为他打得很好，而且没有……
No, I'm not going to play because he is playing well and there is no ego of...
que no, no voy a jugar porque este está jugando bien y no hay ese ego de...
说啊现在我必须比赛，因为我必须比赛，因为我就是我，当这些事情发生时你会理解我
to say ah now I have to play because I have to play because I am me, you understand me when those things happen
de decir ah ya tengo que jugar yo porque tengo que jugar yo porque soy yo me entendés cuando pasan esas cosas
有时它会腐烂一点
sometimes it rots a little
las a veces se se pudre un poco la
苹果
the apple
la manzana.
最后就是事情不顺利的时候。
And in the end is when things don't work out.
Y al final es cuando la cosa no va.
在这些时刻
And in these moments was when
Y en estos momentos fue cuando
事情是因为那是因为教练组所做的也是组建一个小组，其中
The thing was because that was because what the coaching staff also did was put together a group in which
la cosa iba era por eso porque el cuerpo técnico también lo que hizo fue armar un grupo en el que
每个人都知道自己正在扮演的角色，事情就这样发生、发生、发生……
in which each one knew the role they were fulfilling and things went, went, went and...
en el que cada uno sabía el rollo que cumplía y la cosa iba, iba, iba y...
结果会继续发挥作用，并且效果很好，当外部事物良好时，内部更容易反映出来，您可以看到事物的好处
and the results continue to work and well, when things are good on the outside, inside it is reflected much more easily and you can see the good of
y los resultados sigo andando y bueno cuando la cosa está bien afuera adentro se refleja mucho más fácil y se ve lo bueno de
你们每个人都知道他脑子里的感觉，因为当我们聊天时，我们从外面看到了这一点
Each one of you knows what he was feeling with his head because when we chatted, we from the outside saw that
cada uno vos sabés que iba sintiendo con la cabeza porque cuando charlamos nosotros de afuera veíamos eso
因为在任何其他
because in any other
porque en cualquier otro
看来脊椎是不会被遗漏的，你看我们玩的是那些故事
It seems that the spine is not going to be left out, you saw that we play with that story of those
pareces la columna vertebral no va a quedar afuera, viste que nosotros jugamos con esa historia de esas
轮到他在那里了，你也以同样的方式看到了，他发现了一个鼓励的鬼脸
And it was his turn to be there, and you saw it the same way, he found a grimace of encouragement to
Y para él le tocó estar, y vos lo veías igual, encontraba una mueca de aliento para
超越作为新人想成为首发的痛苦
beyond the pain that comes from wanting to be a starter as a newcomer
más allá del dolor que te genera querer ser titular como recién
你在谈话中描述了切尔西，我可以说我正在和你谈论那些在国家队职业生涯的球员。
You described in the talk, Chelsea, I'm talking to you about the players with a career in the national teams, I could say.
describías vos en la charla, lo Chelsea, te estoy hablando de los jugadores con un recorrido en las selecciones, podría decir.
刚好世界杯快到了，他带我出去，亚历克西斯、西恩佐出现了……
Just now that the World Cup is coming, he takes me out and Alexis, Cienzo appeared...
Justo ahora que viene el mundial, me saca y apareció Alexis, Cienzo...
有时我告诉人们，因为它正在翻译工作组是什么，因为说是一回事
and sometimes I tell it to people because it is translating what a work group is because it is one thing to say
y a veces se lo cuento a la gente porque es traducir lo que es un grupo de trabajo porque una cosa es decir
我指望它，另一件事是指望其他地方发生的品丝面，当你看到没有那么精细的调音时。
I bank on it and another thing is to bank on the fret face that happens anywhere else is when you see that there is not that fine tuning.
Yo me la banco y otra cosa es bancarte la cara de traste que pasa en cualquier otro lugar es cuando vos ves que no hay esa sintonía fina.
你说的就是这样，是真的，我刚才告诉你的只是我们刚刚了解到的一点点
and what you say was like that, it was real, what I just told you is a little of what we have just understood
y esto que decís vos era así, era real, esto que te acabo de contar es un poco lo que terminamos de entender
当世界杯结束时。
when the world cup ends.
cuando termina el mundial.
不，是的，我们说的就是这样。
No, yes, what we say is exactly that way.
No, sí, lo que decimos es exactamente de esa manera.
当我玩的时候
when I was playing
cuando estaba jugando
莉亚、恩佐，他在那里，他支持一切，当轮到恩佐进来扮演恩佐时......
Lea, Enzo, he was there, he supported everything and when it was Enzo's turn to come in and play Enzo...
Lea, Enzo, estaba ahí, apoyaba todo y cuando le tocó entrar a Enzo y jugar a Enzo...
他打破了它，然后他继续玩，而莉亚必须参与其中。
He broke it and he continued playing and Lea had to be in it.
la rompió y siguió jugando él y a Lea le tocó estar en él.
坐在板凳上，像最好的人一样训练，并以正确的方式做每件事。
on the bench and trained like the best and did everything the right way.
en el banco y entrenaba como como el mejor y hacía todo de la
最后这也是它给你的......
And in the end that's what it gives you too...
Y al final eso es lo que te da también...
总是有超过 11 名玩家，这很重要，因为最后......
always have more than 11 players, which is important, because in the end...
tener siempre más de 11 jugadores, que es importante, porque al final...
如果 Alexis 不上场，Gio 上场，如果 Enzo 不上场，Lea 上场。
If Alexis doesn't play, Gio plays, if Enzo doesn't play, Lea plays.
Si no juega Alexis juega Gio, si no juega Enzo juega Lea.
团队不会感觉到，不会因为你做出改变而感到不满，因为改变确实存在。
And the team does not feel it, it does not resent because you make change, because there is change.
Y el equipo no lo siente, no se resiente porque haces cambio, porque hay cambio.
对于教练来说，能够拥有这样的球员最终是一种巨大的荣幸。
And that in the end is an enormous privilege for the coach, to be able to have players like that.
Y eso al final para el entrenador es un privilegio enorme, poder tener jugadores así.
每个人都 100% 全力以赴，每个人都知道他们会跌到哪里
that you have everyone at 100% and that everyone knows that where they go down
que a todos los tenés al 100% y que todos saben que en la que bajan
1% 到外面去，这样他们就总有你在那儿、那儿、那儿
1% go outside so they always have you there, there, there
un 1% van para afuera entonces te tiene siempre ahí, ahí, ahí
我认为这是根本性的，而且我认为人们看到的不仅仅是......
and I think that is fundamental and then I think it was seen more than...
y creo que eso es fundamental y después creo que se vio más que...
不幸的是，发生在阿尔昆身上的事情发生在他身上，这比以往任何时候都更好。
More than ever, it is good that what happened to Alcún had happened to him, unfortunately.
más que nunca, está bien que a Alcún le había pasado lo que le pasó, lamentablemente.
但他在世界决赛中为Shio加油，就像没什么一样，
but he was there in the world final, cheering Shio on like it was nothing,
pero estaba ahí en la final del mundo, alentando como si nada a Shio,
被排除在外的
that had been left out of
que había quedado fuera del
我进入了决赛，他们告诉他们来，他们就来了，他们付了那里的公寓费用
I was in the final, they told them to come and they came, they paid for an apartment to be there
estaba en la final, les dijeron para que venga y se vinieron, se pagaron un departamento para estar ahí
带着想来的家人，无论如何，穆索也来了。
with the family that wanted to come, whatever, Musso came too.
con la familia que quiso venir, lo que sea, Musso también vino.
那些被排除在外的球员来了，他们在其他时候也来了
The players who had been left out came, who had been at other times
vinieron los jugadores que habían quedado afuera, que habían estado en otros momentos
在那里你会意识到团队中存在的团结，在那里你会意识到每个人之间存在的感情。
And there you realize the unity that exists in the group, there you realize the affection that exists between everyone.
Y ahí vos te da cuenta la unión que hay en el grupo, ahí vos te da cuenta el cariño que hay entre todos.
没有自我，什么都没有，最终这就是给你的……因为我们不仅仅是……
that there are no egos, that there is nothing and in the end that is what gives you that... because we were not just...
que no hay egos, que no hay nada y al final eso es lo que te da esa... porque no éramos solamente...
26 说我们参加了世界杯，但后来在决赛中......
26 that we were there in the World Cup, but later in that final...
26 que estábamos ahí en el mundial, sino que después en esa final...
另外四五个人也来了，当时更衣室里我们差不多有三十个人。
Four or five other guys had come and in the locker room there were almost thirty of us then.
había venido cuatro o cinco chicos más y en el vestuario éramos casi treinta entonces
到最后，正能量不再是那26个人，而是有人
In the end, that positive energy is no longer more than the 26 that were there, but rather having people
al final ahí esa energía positiva ya no es más de los 26 que estaban sino tener gente
这给你带来了一种美丽的能量，他们想要的就是看到你成为世界冠军，他们……
that comes to you with a beautiful energy that all they want is to see you be world champion and they...
que te viene con una energía linda que lo único que quieren es que verte ser campeón del mundo y ellos...
比如说，我就是这样想的，我看到Gio像没人管的那样胡闹……
For example, I think about it that way, I saw Gio messing around like nobody's business...
Por ejemplo, yo lo pienso de esa manera, yo lo veía a Gio petejar como si nadie...
可惜当时我没能成为世界冠军。
What a shame it is that I couldn't be world champion at that time.
Qué lástima me da que no haya podido ser campeón del mundo en ese momento.
后来当我们在一起时，无论如何，我的妻子避开了他并告诉他
And later when we were together, whatever, my wife avoided him and told him
Y después cuando estábamos juntos, lo que sea, lo evitaba mi mujer que le decía
奇沃，你还会有另一次机会，你会报仇的，因为我不知道你小时候是什么样的。
Chivo, you're going to have another chance, you're going to have revenge, because I don't know what you are like as a boy.
Chivo, vas a tener otra oportunidad, vas a tener la revancha, porque no me sé cómo sos como chico.
然后他突然再次赢得了美洲杯冠军，然后……
and out of nowhere he won the Copa América again, then...
y a la nada una Copa América la volvió a ganar de vuelta, entonces...
到最后，一切美好的事情都会降临到你身上，什么也没有，我想就是这样，就是这样。
In the end, everything good ends up coming to you and nothing, I think it's like that, it's that way.
Al final todo lo bueno te termina llegando y nada, creo que es así, es de esa manera.
两场决赛我不会再打扰你了 蒙蒂尔容纳球
two finals and I won't bother you anymore Montiel accommodates the ball
dos finales y ya no te molesto más Montiel acomoda la pelota
明天就是两年了，你随处可见的所有图像都会爆炸。
Tomorrow it will be two years, all the images that you will see everywhere will explode.
mañana van a ser dos años te va a explotar todas las imágenes que vas a ver por todos lados
告诉我关于蒙蒂尔的那次旅程、那次行走、那次想法。
Tell me about that journey through Montiel, that walk, that thought.
contame ese recorrido de Montiel, esa caminata, ese pensamiento.
我们都看到了这些图像。
We all saw the images.
todos veíamos las imágenes.
当我去蒙蒂尔时我说它今天不能关门。
When I went to Montiel I said it can't close today.
Yo cuando iba cuando iba a Montiel yo decía hoy no puede cerrar.
这些你都做了吗？
Have you been doing all of them?
¿Venís haciendo todas?
今天你要关门了。
Today you are going to close.
Hoy vas a cerrar.
不，不是今天。
No, not today.
No, hoy no.
今天你不能关闭。
Today you can't close.
Hoy no podés cerrar.
今天正是时候。
Today is the time.
Hoy es el momento.
我当时唯一想说的是，今天怎么会奇怪呢？
The only thing I was saying at that time, how is it going to be weird today?
Lo único que decía en ese momento, ¿cómo va a ser raro hoy?
你从来没有刮过，你今天要刮，不是今天，今天它就进去了。
You never scraped, you're going to scrape today, not today, today it goes inside.
no raste nunca, vas a rar hoy, hoy no, hoy va adentro.
我有很大的信心，事实是我有很大的信心......
I had a lot of faith, the truth is that I had a lot of faith in...
Tenía mucha fe, la verdad que tenía mucha fe en...
在冈萨，事实是我被说服了，但是，神经和……
In Gonza the truth is that I was convinced, but well, the nerves and...
En Gonza la verdad que estaba convencido, pero bueno, los nervios y...
所有关于这仍然是一个点球以及任何事情都可能发生的事情，因为事情就是这样。
and all that about how it's still a penalty and that anything can happen because that's how it is.
y todo eso de que igual es un penal y que todo puede pasar porque es así.
我在那里，但我有很大的信心，但当我看到弓箭手已经转向另一边时，我什么也没有
I was there but I had a lot of faith and nothing when I only saw that the archer had already turned to the other side
estaba pero tenía mucha fe y nada cuando yo vi solamente que el arquero ya se había tirado para el otro lado
内心的喜悦和爆炸是巨大的。
The joy, the explosion of the heart was enormous.
la alegría, la explosión del corazón era enorme.
阿根廷人民的历史，你们所引发的民众示威，给了你们最超然的快乐之一。
The history of the Argentine people, the popular demonstration that you generated, has given you one of the most transcendent joys.
le han dado de las alegrías más trascendentes la historia del pueblo argentino, la manifestación popular que ustedes generaron
再见！
Bye bye!
¡Adiós!
太棒了
it was amazing
fue increíble
这会发生，因为你看到他和科拉平托在一起，他正在努力弥补自己的方式，而且那里有很多人
it will happen because you see him with colapinto who is trying to make up his way and a lot of people are there
pasará porque lo ves con colapinto que está tratando de saldar su camino y está ahí un montón de gente
网球运动员在做什么？
What are the tennis players doing?
que van los tenistas
这根浅蓝色和白色的蜡烛，它真的很疯狂，这就是你为小孩子带来的自豪感
this light blue and white candle and it really goes crazy that's the pride that you have generated that thing about little kids
esta vela celeste y blanca y se vuelve loca realmente eso es el orgullo que han generado ustedes esa cosa de que los pibes chiquitos
他们不在阿根廷踢球，但他们说我想为国家队效力。
They don't play in Argentina and they say I want to play for the national team.
que no juegan en la Argentina y dice yo quiero jugar en la selección.
好吧，还有很多其他足球运动员。
and well, and a lot of other footballers.
y bueno, y un montón de futbolistas más.
我想用微笑来结束这次演讲，对此我深表感谢。
I want to bring a smile to close part of this talk, for which I thank you immensely.
Quiero apelar una sonrisa para cerrar parte de esta charla que te agradezco inmensamente.
我希望这一切结束
I want this to end
quiero que se termine esta
到此结束，真相就到这里了。
This ends it, here is the truth.
Con esto se termina, acá es la verdad.
老实说，我不知道，因为我总是读《罗德里和矮人》，他总是说它们是事实，它们是事实。
I don't know, honestly, because I always read Rodri and the dwarf, he always says that they are fact, that they are fact.
No sé, la verdad, porque siempre lea Rodri y el enano, siempre tira que son hecho, que son hecho.
但我们可以讨论那个中心。
But we can discuss that center.
Pero podemos discutir ese centro.
确实，他们赢得了一些比赛，这是事实。
It's true that they won some of the tournaments, that's true.
Es verdad que ganaron algunos de los torneos, eso es verdad.
但是，嘿，这很难...
But hey, it's hard to...
Pero bueno, es difícil de...
说，但是嘿，是的，让我们继续讨论吧，这样他们就不会生气或发生任何事情。
to say, but hey, yes, let's move on to it so they don't get angry or anything.
de decir, pero bueno, sí, vamos a darle pa'lante a ello para que no se enojen ni nada.
我们将把这种自我放在一边，让他们三个继续保持最好的状态。
We are going to put that ego aside a little and we are going to let the three of them continue as the best.
Vamos a dejar un poco ese ego de costado y lo vamos a dejar que sigan ellos tres como los mejores.
事实是，安杰利托，谢谢你，因为就像我和许多足球运动员一样，
The truth is, Angelito, thank you because, as happens to me with many footballers,
la verdad Angelito gracias porque como me pasa con muchos futbolistas
当你开始梦想时，我看到你在一流足球中取得了成绩
I saw you making grades in first class football when you were starting to dream
te vi haciéndote notas en fútbol de primera cuando empezabas a soñar
我可以给你最后一张关于迪斯普尔在场上穿着国家队球衣的信息
I was able to give you the last note for Dispor on the field dressed as a player with the national team shirt that
Te pude hacer la última nota por Dispor en la cancha vestido de jugador con la camiseta de la selección que
他所说的话都会从那些小地方为我记录下来
It will be recorded for me from those little places what he said about
quedará grabada para mí desde esos lugares chiquititos lo que decía de
改进的本能，以及他长期以来欠我的关于你的表现的谈话。
the instinct to improve and this talk that he owed me about how you're doing for a long time.
el instinto de superación y esta charla que me debía en cómo te va desde hace mucho tiempo.
我们经常这样说，人们对在逆境中奋斗所产生的效果非常钦佩。
There is a very great admiration, and we say this constantly, of that effect of having fought in adversity.
Hay una admiración muy grande, y lo decimos permanentemente, de ese efecto de haber luchado en la adversidad.
我们感到完全认同，所以非常感谢您从根本上感谢您愿意交谈。
We feel fully identified, so thank you very much and for your willingness, fundamentally, to talk.
Nos sentimos plenamente identificados así que infinitas gracias y por la predisposición fundamentalmente para la charla.
不，不客气，不客气。
No, you're welcome, you're welcome.
No, de nada, de nada.
快乐是我的。
The pleasure is mine.
El placer es mío.
我已经答应过你我们会做到这一点，有时需要一段时间，我很难说话，然后当我开始说话时......
I had promised you that we were going to do it, it takes a while sometimes, it's hard for me to talk, then when I start talking...
Te había prometido que lo íbamos a hacer, tardo un poco a veces, me cuesta hablar, después cuando me largo a hablar...
我不会停下来，但一开始这对我来说很难，但我已经答应过你了。
I don't stop, but it's hard for me at first, but I already promised you.
No paro, pero me cuesta al principio, pero ya te lo había prometido.
我知道你怎么样，我知道你一直在那里，但什么也没有，谢谢你的留言，我希望你能找到它
I know how you are, I know that you were always there, and nothing, thank you for the note, I hope you find it
sé cómo sos, sé que siempre estuviste ahí, y nada, agradecerte por la nota, espero que le
你喜欢它，结果很好，没什么好的，祝你假期愉快
that you liked it, that it turned out well and nothing good, wish you a happy holiday
que le haya gustado, que haya salido bien y bueno nada, desearles una feliz fiesta
致所有在场且身体健康的人，希望在 2025 年
to all those who are there and well, hopefully in 2025
a todos los que están ahí y bueno, ojalá que el 2025
祝您身体健康并带着
May you come in good health and with
que venga con mucha salud y con
而且，我告诉你，如果你也想成为一名专栏作家，为什么不把自己放在一边呢？
What's more, I tell you, if you want to be a columnist too, why not set yourself aside.
Es más, te digo, si querés ser columnista también, porque no te tirés aparte.
这里有法比安·库韦罗（Fabián Cubero），你看到他让我们玩得很开心，我希望你不要排除他，他在电视上会是一个奢侈品。
Here we have Fabián Cubero, you saw that he makes us have a little fun, I hope you don't rule him out, he would be a luxury on TV.
Acá lo tenemos a Fabián Cubero, viste que nos hace divertir un poco, oja no la descartes, sería un lujo en tele.
比安卡说得很好，呵呵。
Bianca speaks very well, huh.
Bianca habla muy bien, eh.
比安卡·马克西·罗德里格斯的表现还不错，呵呵。
Bianca Maxi Rodríguez is not doing so badly, huh.
Bianca Maxi Rodríguez tan mal no le va, eh.
嗯，是的，事实是，有时会有一点液体。
Eh, yes, the truth is, from time to time the liquids are a little bit there.
Eh, sí, la verdad que sí, de vez en cuando los líquidos un poquito ahí.
他们到处都是一样的，他们无处不在。
They are everywhere the same, they are everywhere.
Están todos lados igual, están todos lados.
多么伟大的小天使啊，对家人的爱，恭喜你
what a great little angel, love to the family, congratulations to you
que grande angelito cariños a la familia felicidades para vos
并继续享受足球最美的事情，那就是踢球。
also and continue enjoying the most beautiful thing about football, which is playing ball.
también y seguir disfrutando de lo más lindo que tiene el fútbol que es jugar a la pelota.
嗯，非常感谢，一个大大的拥抱。
Well, thank you very much, a big hug.
Bueno, muchísimas gracias, un abrazo muy grande.
超。
Chao.
简而言之，Angelito de Di María，我们为什么要做出更多贡献？
Simply put, Angelito de Di María, why are we going to contribute anything more?
Simplemente, Angelito de Di María, ¿para qué vamos a aportar algo más?